--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
翻译: CMCT-ELP小组    压制: 玄子
招募Q号: 76846146
有一个问题是：
NARRATOR: One question:
为什么会有那么丰富的物种？
Why is there such a stunning diversity of life?
答案是：进化论
One answer: Evolution.
查尔斯·达尔文的伟大发现
Charles Darwin's  brilliant theory
阐述了各物种如何适应自然和进化
that explains how species adapt end change.
它被人们称颂为最伟大的发现
It's been called the best idea anyone ever had.
但还有一个大问题：
But there's one big problem:
进化论实际上是如何影响生物进化的过程的？
How does it actually work?
现在，卓越的科学为你解答这一问题
Now,extraordinary science is answering that question.
揭开这个隐藏机制的神秘面纱
It is uncovering the hidden mechanisms
从生物体内开始
inside creatures' bodies
它可以解释这些惊人的演变过程
that can explain astonishing transformations,
就像一些恐龙进化成了现在的鸟类...
like how birds can evolve from dinosaurs...
为什么鱼类曾经是你的祖先...
why a fish was once your ancestor...
以及最重要的，究竟是什么造就了我们人类
and,above all,what makes us human.
现在，在NOVA节目中
Right new on NOVA,
你会发现一些连达尔文也不知道的东西
you'll find out what Darwin never knew.
NOVA主要由如下企业赞助：
Major funding for NOVA is provided by the following:
埃克森美孚
ExxonMobil,
承担世界上最艰难的能源挑战
taking on the world's toughest energy challenges.
同时感谢戴维·科赫
And by David H.Koch.
以及...
And...
公共广播公司
And by the Corporation for Public Broadcasting
以及以下给PBS的特别赞助
and by contributions to your PBS station from:
普洛麦格集团
Additional funding by Promega Corporation,
天天新发现
discovering every day.
普洛麦格，生命的科学
Promega,the science of life.
同时感谢威斯康辛校友研究基金会
And by the Wisconsin Alumni Research Foundation,
给予威斯康辛大学的鼎力支持
in support of the University of Wisconsin.
在地球上，生命之树有着惊人丰富的种类
NARRATOR: The Tree of Life on earth is one of stunning diversity.
9000多种鸟
9.000 species of birds.
350000种昆虫
350,000 kinds of beetles.
28000种鱼
28,000 types of fish.
总共有两百万种生物
Two million living species and counting.
而我们，只是其中的一种
And we are just one of them.
（鸟鸣声）
(birds calling)
但是为什么动物种类繁多？
But why is there such an amazing variety of animals?
为什么鱼的种类琳琅满目？
Why are there so many types of fish?
为什么昆虫又千奇百怪？
So many different species of beetle?
这么多不同的生物
How did this extraordinary
是怎么产生的？
profusion of life on earth come about?
今天，我们非常高兴
Today,we celebrate the man
因为我们可以解决这些问题了
who would ultimately answer that question.
查尔斯·达尔文
Charles Darwin.
他出生于两百年前
He was born 200 years ago
150年前，他发表了他的巨作
and it is 150 years since he published the work
那是我们
that has become the bedrock
研究地球上生物的里程碑
of our understanding of life on earth.
塔宾：达尔文所想弄明白的
CLIFF TABIN: What Darwin wanted
是地球为什么有
to understand was how you get
如此丰富的物种
this eotraordinary diversity of life on earth.
他完全正确.
He was spot on.
他真的成功了.
He really nailed it.
达尔文的理论革命
NARRATOR: Darwin's theory of evolution--
他的理论解释了各个物种是如何进化的
his account of why species adapt and change--
被称为最完美的理论
has been called the best idea anyone ever had.
但达尔文承认：他的工作还没有完善
But even Darwin admitted that his work was incomplete.
很多问题还是不能回答
Vast questions ware still unanswered.
那么，最大的问题是：
And the biggest question was: How?
这个巨大的变革是怎样在地球开始的
How did evolution take place?
卡罗尔: 他不知道到底是什么动力促使这些变化
SEAN CARROLL: He didn't know any of the mechanics of that process.
他不明白这些物质的力量
he didn't understand the physical forces
改变了生物进化的过程
that would actually change the way species appeared.
但是，在今天
NARRATOR: But today,
我们可以解答这些达尔文不知道的问题了
we can answer the questions that Darwin could not.
我们可以看清进化的本质
We can look under the hood of evolution
清楚神奇的进化过程
and see exactly how this mysterious process
是如何使得物种千变万化的.
gives rise to such astounding diversity.
塔宾: 从科学的角度来讲，
TABIN:What's incredible about this time
最让我们难以置信的是
from a scientific perspective is,
我们逐渐可以理解自然界的物种多样性
we're going to be able to understand that diversity.
这使我们十分兴奋
And that just adds to the excitement.
它不再笼罩着神秘的面纱
It doesn't demystify it.
它使这一切更神奇
It makes it all the more magical.
这---就是神秘的进化论
NARRATOR:And this is the magic and mystery of evolution.
一个单一的物种，经过亿万年的演变，衍生出众多物种
Over eons of time,a single species gives rise to many.
古老的鱼成为了
An ancient fish evolves to become the ancestor
爬行动物的祖先，甚至包括我们
of all four-limbed animals,even us.
人类，这一种生物，
And one species,our own,
逐渐产生了独一无二而又复杂的大脑
develops e large and uniquely complex brain,
使得我们主宰了这个地球
enabling us to dominate the planet.
这个研究回答了
This is the search for the answers
达尔文一直都不明白的问题
to what Darwin never knew.
（儿童交谈声）
(children chattering)
达尔文从小就对自然有独特的情感
Darwin began his love affair with nature when ha was a child,
和现在很多他的追随者一样
jest like many of his modern followers,
包括进化论和生物学家，肖恩·卡罗尔
including evolutionary biologist,Sean Carroll.
卡罗尔：我培养我对动物的兴趣
CARROLL: I developed my interest in animals the same way I think
和很多生物学家一样
most biologists did,which was either
一般去后院园子或者去动物园
going out in the backyard or going to zoos.
一旦有机会出现，我会立刻抓住
And anytime I got a chance,I'd flip over logs
去寻找蝾螈
and look for salamanders
蛇，青蛙等等这些小动物
and snakes and frogs and things like this.
我对它们的行为着迷
And I was just fascinated with their patterns and behavior.
年轻的查尔斯·达尔文亦是如此
NARRATOR:So it was with the young Charles Darwin.
卡罗尔：年轻的查尔斯喜欢在野外溜达
CARRALL:Young Charles liked to traipse around the outdoors.
他喜欢收集各种昆虫等东西
He loved to collect beetles and things.
他完全就是普通的孩子
He was a completeld ordinary kid.
不喜欢学校
And he didn't like school.
事实上，达尔文这可怜的学生
In fact,he was such a poor student that his father,
连他爸爸，这成功而又仪表堂堂的医生
a rather successful physician and a pretty imposing figure,
都对达尔文的人生之路十分忧心
was worried about Darwin's direction in life.
所以他父亲把他送到了爱丁堡
NARRATOR: So his father packed him off to Edinburgh,
最有名的医学院，想他成为一个医生
the finest medical school in Europe,to become a doctor.
但年轻的达尔文太过于拘谨
But young Charles was just too squeamish.
卡罗尔：他被这个医学院深深震惊了
CCRROLL: And he was really horrified by medical school.
他亲眼目睹了一次儿童手术
He witnessed an operation on a child
而且是在没有麻醉的情况下
and this is in the era before anesthetics.
他逃离了手术室并发誓不再回去
And he just fled the operating theater vowing never to return.
接着，他父亲把他送到
NARRATOR:Next,his father sent him
剑桥大学去学做一个牧师
to Cambridge to study for the clergy.
达尔文还是没有坚持下来
He didn't succeed at that either,
但是他却找到了他的人生方向
but he did find his direction in life,
恢复了他孩童时代对自然的兴趣
reviving his childhood interest in nature.
卡罗尔：达尔文开始了他在生物多样性方面的研究
CARROLL: Darwin starts on his path to his divinity degree
作为一个学生，他慢慢地成熟了
anh he starts to mature as a student.
他对某些科目更加的认真对待
He becomes more serious about some subjects,
特别是自然历史学，并且学到了很多关于
particularly natural history,and he learns a lot more
植物学和地理学方面的知识
about botany and about geology and these things.
他成为了一个出色的科学家
he's becoming a pretty solid field scientist.
作为一个自然学家
NARRATOR: His reputation as a naturalist
他获得巨大的荣誉
gained him a spectacular invitation.
卡罗尔：达尔文被派遣到了
CARROLL: Charles was offered a place
一艘英国海军军舰——贝格尔号
on the British Navy ship the HMS Beagle,
那艘军舰平时负责南美洲的巡航
whose mission was to survey the waters around South America.
贝格尔号的船长想找一个饱读诗书的
Now,the captain of the Beagle wanted a well-educated,
懂科学 可以一起聚餐
scientific person aboard,and a dinner companion,
一起谈天说地的伙伴
somodody to share conversation with.
达尔文就完全符合这些要求
And Darwin fit the bill perfectly.
就这样 达尔文踏上了改变他一生的旅途
NARRATOR: And so,Charles Darwin set off on a fateful voyage
它使我们对大自然多样性的认识
that would revolutionize our understanding
有了翻天覆地的变化
of life's great diversity.
达尔文在贝格尔号上的旅途差不多有5年之久
The voyage of the Beagle took nearly five years.
从佛得角群岛出发
It wove its way from the Cape Verde islands
沿着巴西的海岸线一直走
and along the coast of Brazil.
当到了阿根廷的时候
It was in Argentina that ha made
达尔文有了第一个重要的研究发现
his first important discovery.
卡罗尔：在旅途的早些时候
CARROLL:Early on in the voyage,
达尔文发现了一些让人惊讶的化石
Darwin found some amazing fossils.
他挖出一些巨型哺乳动物的
He dug up some skulls,sown jaws,some backbones
头骨、颚、脊骨等等
of what turned out to be giant mammals.
这些生物显然已经灭绝，而达尔文开始思考
Now,these were clearly extinct and Darwin began to ponder,
这些化石和现在
what was the relationship of those fossils
生活在南美洲的动物有什么联系呢
to the living animals of South America.
达尔文行进中，来到一个停靠港，
NARRATOR: But one port of call on Darwin's voyage
这个港口，将会证明是最重要的那个.
proved more important than all the others.
它，就是加拉帕戈斯群岛.
The Galapagos.
此岛由13个孤立小岛组成的群岛
This cluster of 13 isolated islands
在离厄瓜多尔600英里的太平洋中
lies 600 miles off the coast of Ecuador in the Pacific Ocean.
这里是很多不寻常动物的乐园
These islands are home to unusual animals
在地球其他地方都看不到这样的景象
found nowhere else on earth.
企鹅竟然生活在赤道上 在暖水里游泳
Penguins that live at the equator and swim in warm water,
而不是在南极冰冷的海水当中
instead of the frigid seas of the South Pole.
巨龟有600英镑重
Giant tortoises that weigh up to 600 pounds.
绿鬣蜥 巨型的蜥蜴在海水里游泳和潜水
Iguanas,huge lizards that swim and dive in the sea.
不同于其它地方 他们只住在岛上
Everywhere else,they dwell only on land.
（狗叫声）
(barking)
第一次去加拉帕戈斯群岛时，
Traveling for the first time in the Galapagos,
肖恩·卡罗尔看到使达尔文异常好奇的
Sean Carroll is seeing the same creatures
同样景象
that so intrigued Darwin.
卡罗尔：在所有的动物当中 我觉得海洋鬣蜥
CARROLL: Of all animals,I think these marine iguanas
是加拉帕戈斯最具代表性的象征
are the greatest symbol of the Galagagos,
也是我在这里最想看到的
what I most wanted to see here.
希望观察他们的生活习惯
And to see them in their native habitat,
和那黑岩浑然一体
blending against that black rock,
就像达尔文描述的那样
just as Darwin described it...
这让人无比的激动
It's an absolute thrill.
这是一个面目狰狞的生物
DARWIN(dramatized):It's a hideous looking creature,
脏脏的黑色的外表
of a dirty black color,
移动起来笨拙、呆滞
stupid and sluggish in its movements.
他们的外表和土地一样黑
They're as black as the porous rocks over which they crawl.
达尔文在他的日志里描述了绿鬣蜥
NARRTTOR: Derwic meticulously described the iguanas in his diary.
但那时，他还与日后将成为的科学权威
But he was far from the scientific authority
相距甚远
he would become.
卡罗尔：那时的达尔文
CARROLL: The Darwin that arrived here
并不是我现在说的伟大的理论家
was not the great theorist that we know today.
他只是一个26岁的收藏家
He was a 26-year-old collector,collecting
几乎是随机的收藏各种植物
really,almost at randow,any kind of plants,
各种动物和各种石头
any kind of animals,any kinds of rocks.
他甚至不知道他收藏的这些东西有什么意义
He didn't even know the meaning
知道后来才被发现它的价值
of what he was collecting until much later.
他也对巨龟非常着迷
NARRATOR: He was also tascinated by the giant tortoises,
那些巨龟甚至允许他骑在它们的背上
which allowed him to ride on their backs
慢慢的在地上挪动
as they slowly lumbered around.
达尔文：我经常爬到它们的背上
DARWIN: I frequently got on their backs
坐在它们的外壳上说唱
and then,upon giving a few raps on the hinder part of the shell,
他们就会起身爬走
they would rise up and walk away.
但是我这时会很难保持身体的平衡
But I found it very difficult to keep my balance.
达尔文测试这些生物到底缓慢到什么地步
NARRATOR: Darwin measured the creatures' extreme slowness.
他算了一下，一天才爬4英里
About four miles a day,he calculated.
但是当地人知道
But the local people knew
关于这些乌龟的其他事情
something else about the tortoises.
他们可以仅凭看他们的龟壳
(whispering): They could tell which island any tortoise came from
说出这些龟是来自哪个小岛的
jest by looking at its shell.
它们的龟壳根据
NARRATOR: Their shells differed
它们居住的小岛的环境而不同
depending on which island they lived on.
有些龟的壳塑造成一个拱顶的形状
Some tortoises had shells shaped like a dome.
有些则有一道飞弧在头上，就像一个鞍状
Others had shells arcing over their heeds like a saddle.
有些就是颜色略有差异
Others differed subtly in color.
或者可以从龟壳的底部看出来
Or by how much thu bottom of the shell flared out.
达尔文已经慢慢找到
Darwin had literally been sitting on a clue--
理解生物多样性途径的线索
a way to understand the great diversity of life,
但他还是没有意识到
but he didn't yet realize it.
（鸟鸣声）
(birds calling)
相反，达尔文把他的注意力移到了鸟类身上
Instead,Darwin turned his attention to birds.
这些小岛上遍地都是各种貌似是
The islands were full of what seemed to be
相似物种的种群
a familiar assortment of species.
所以，他拿起袋子收集
So,he stuffed his collecting bag
他认为属于雀类的鸟
with what he thought were types of finches,
锡嘴雀、鹪鹩和画眉
grosbeaks,wrens and blackbirds.
五周之后，在加拉帕戈斯
And then,after five weeks in the Galapagos,
达尔文去了太平洋其他的港口
Darwin and the Beagle went to other ports in the Pacific
进行回家前的最后一次航行
and finally set sail for home.
回到了陆地，他开始整理他在旅途中
On board,ha started to sort through
在这整整五年时间里
the vast number of specimens he had collected
收集的大量物种
on the five-year voyage.
但是一直到他回到英国
But it was not until he returned to Britain
才能发现它们的价值
that ha was able to make sense of them.
它开启了一个翻天覆地的变革
It began with a starting revelation.
达尔文收集的各种鸟类
All the different birds he had collected
其实由一种变异衍变而来的
actually were variations of a single type.
卡罗尔：达尔文留意到，他在加拉帕戈斯收集了
CARROLL: He learns that those birds he had collected on the Galapagos
代表了13种雀
actually represent 13 different species of finch.
然而，这些鸟长得差异很大却使达尔文困惑
NARRATOR: What misled Darwin was that they looked radically different.
有些鸟有宽而强硬的喙
Some had wide,tough beaks.
有些的喙却有长又细
Others had long slender ones.
而这些不同的特征和它们居住的小岛有着密切关系
And these differences depended on which islands they lived on.
卡罗尔：为什么会这样
CARROLL: Now,why would that be?
为什么不同种类的
Why would there be slightly different birds,
不同种群的小鸟分布在不同的小岛上
slightly different species on different islands
而这都发生在这个世界上的同一小角落？
all in one part of the world?
达尔文回想起加拉帕戈斯的海龟
NARRATOR: Darwin now thought back to the Galapagos tortoises.
不同海岛上的海龟差异非常大
They too differed from island to island.
他觉得慢慢明白了
His brain began racing.
卡罗尔：想法慢慢成为思想了
CARROLL: Thoughts are starting to crystallize,
在他脑海里一点一点地慢慢凝聚起来
take shape in his mind,bit by bit,bit by bit.
他描述这个过程为精神震撼
He starts this process he describes as mental rioting.
在浩瀚的思绪中
Just stream of consciousness
他一点一点的记录那些头绪
where he's jotting down note after note after note.
思想自动浮现在他脑海中
Thoughts as they occur to him.
最后 他把所有思想总结成一点
And finally,they converge on this one idea.
达尔文现在意识到
NARRATOR: What Darwin now realized
因为某些原因，各个物种发生了某种变化
was that somehow,for some reason,species change.
在之前，它们肯定
Originally,there must have been
同属于加拉帕戈斯群岛的一个物种
just one type of finch in the Galapagos,
不过，随着时间的推移，这个物种衍变分化
but over time it had diversified
产生了长着各种喙的种群
into many kinds,with different beak shapes.
海龟的衍变也是同样的道理
The same for the tortoises.
一个海龟种群经过衍变产生了众多不同的种群
One type of tortoise must have turned into many kinds,
因为居住的小岛的环境不同，它们长出了不同的龟壳
with different shells depending on which island they lived on.
带着这个深刻的理解
With this great insight,
达尔文走进了新的危险的境地
Darwin entering dangerous new territory.
那个时代的标准观念是
The standard view at the time
上帝创造了各个物种
was that God had created every species.
上帝做的就是最好的
And that what God had created was perfect
不容许丝毫改变
and could not change.
卡罗尔：但是达尔文敢说不
CARROLL: But Darwin said no.
为什么造物主会不厌其烦地造出
Why would the Creator bother with making
有细小差别的鸟雀
slightly different finches
分布在不同而又无多大差别的小岛上？
for each of these different islands that all looked alike?
当时流行的观点无法解释这一个问题
NARRTTOR: The prevailing view just didn't make sense.
但这仅是达尔文革命的开始
But this was only the beginning of Darwin's revolution.
他把注意力转移到了化石上
He turned his attention to the fossils
化石是从南美洲收集起来的
he had collected in South America.
其中一个是巨型的树懒
One was of a giant sloth.
另外一个是巨大的犰狳样的生物
Another was of a huge armadillo-like creature.
这些动物现在都已经灭绝了
These animals were extinct,
不过小型树懒仍然存在与今天的南美洲
but little sloths still existed in South America.
一些体积较小的犰狳也是如此
And so did smaller armadillos.
这意味着什么呢
What could this mean?
卡罗尔：他觉得他们非常相像
CARROLL: It dawned on him that they resembled each other.
所以，他认为这些被发现的化石
So,what he had found in the ground
就是现在生活在南美洲的动物的祖先
were the buried ancestors of the living animals of South America.
这又是一个关于物种进化的
NARRATOR: So,again,here was more evidence
有力的证据
that species changed.
这些动物的祖先经过漫长岁月的衍变
Somehow,these ancient giants must have been transformed
成为了今天这些体积较小的生物
into the smaller creatures we see today.
但是达尔文后来的发现
But what Darwin would later find out
把物种进化论发展
took this idea of how species change
成为人们的共识
into a completely new league.
在维多利亚女王的时代 科学家惯常地
In Victorian times,scientists routinely
从生物的胚胎期研究生命的成长
studied life-forms at the embryonic stage.
这些生物是如何从单个细胞成长为
How these tiny forms develop from just e single cell
一个完整的生命体
into an entire creature has long been seen
这一直被视为自然的鬼斧神工的杰作
as one of the wonders of nature.
观察胚胎的成长
Watching a developing embryo
实在是自然界最壮观、最惊人的事情
is truly the most glorious miracle of nature.
我的意思是，无以伦比
I mean,you know,no bologna.
对胚胎的研究，使达尔文异常震惊
NARRATOR: What Darwin learned from studying the embryos amazed him.
在蛇的胚胎，你可以看到微小的隆起
In snake embryos,you could see tiny bumps.
这些有着骨雏形的蛇蛋
The bony rudiments of legs.
却不会长成一个成年的蛇
But these would never develop in the adult snake.
达尔文觉得很奇怪 蛇是因为某种原因
Darwin wondered,Were snakes somehow
从别的会生蛋的动物衍变而来的吗
descended from animals with legs?
他认识到成年的鲸鱼没有牙齿
He learned that whales,which have no teeth as adults,
但是胚胎期的却有
had them as embryos.
这些牙齿在它们出生之前就消失了
Those teeth disappeared before they were born.
对达尔文而言，这意味着
To Darwin,it had to mean
鲸鱼是长着牙齿的生物的后裔
whales were descended from creatures with teeth.
人类的胚胎则提供了更惊人的证据
But human embryos provided the most startling evidence.
在显微镜下面
Under the microscope,
脖子的细小的夹缝清晰可见
tiny slits around the neck were clearly visible.
和鱼类有着同样的特征
Exactly the same structures were found in fish.
但是鱼的夹缝变成了鳃
But in fish,they turned into gills
人类的则变成了内耳的骨头
In humans,they became the bones of our inner ear.
这很明确的表示人类其实是鱼的后裔
Surely,this showed that humans must be descended from fish.
这是一个让人震惊的想法
It's an astonishing thought.
贾德森：我不知道你的祖先，我的祖先
JUDSON: I don't know about your ancestors,but mine included
包括神父的，这是个大家通常都会猜想的问题
priests and,you know,the,the usual,the usual suspects.
但是这个关乎我们全部人的研究发现指明
But the idea that all of us have,have fish
鱼是我们家族的一员，实在是让人很惊讶
in our family tree,I think it's amazing.
现在，达尔文得出了一个惊人的结论
NARRATOR: And so,Darwin arrived at an astonishing conclusion,
一个对物种多样性
one that would become central to his understanding
有着的深刻理解的思想
of the great diversity of life.
达尔文得出惊人的大胆的结论---所有的生命
Darwin had this amazingly bold idea-- the Tree of Life--
所有的物种都是有联系的
that all species were connected.
这意味着，只要你追溯历史足够远
And what it meant was,it you go far enough back
在我们人类家族里，你会发现祖先是条鱼
in our family tree of humans,you'll come to fish.
在鸟类的家族里 如果你追溯历史足够远
If you go far enough back in the family tree of birds,
你会发现祖先是条恐龙
you'll come to dinosaurs.
那些看着非常不像的生物
So that creatures that don't look
其实都是有着深刻的联系的
anything at all like each other are actually deeply connected.
在达尔文之前 从来没有人得出这样的结论
No one came close to having this idea before Darwin.
这是一个对于
NARRATOR: This seemed to be an explanation
生物多样性的解释
for the vast diversity of animals.
他们有着共同的祖先
Beginning with a common ancestor,
经过时间的推移
over time across generations,
物种发生了显著的变化
species could change dramatically.
有些增加了新的身体特征
Some might add new body features.
有些则没有了某些特征
Others might drop them.
最终，一个的生物
Ultimately,one typo of creature
变成了各种各样不同的物种
could be transformed into something utterly different.
这个过程达尔文称之为：后代渐变
It's a process Darwin called "descent with modification."
但是这就有问题了
Bat it all begged a question.
这是为什么呢？
Why?
是什么促使生物改衍变？
What was making creatures change?
达尔文需要一些线索
Darwin needed clues.
他在一个让人非常吃惊的地方找到了
And he found them in a very surprising place.
---狗
Dogs.
大的、小的、肥的、高的
Big,small,fat,tall.
英国人长期以来一直对它痴迷
The British have long been obsessed by them.
在维多利亚女王时代的英国 人们对狗有着深深的喜爱之情
It was a full-blown love affair in Victorian England.
甚至女皇也为狗而疯狂
Even Her Majesty was dog crazy.
这种喜爱之情一直延续到现在
That love affair still continues today.
特别是在科学家之中，例如国家的卫生研究院的
Especially among scientists like Heidi Parker
海蒂·帕克
at the National Institutes of Health.
一个关于狗的最有趣的事情
So,one of the most interesting things about dogs
是狗产生了人类也有的变异
is the kind of variation that you have.
狗有像土拔鼠般大小的
We have dogs the size of groundhogs
有像可以长成骡子般大小的
versus a dog like Zeppie,the Leonberger,
比如莱昂贝格尔狗
who can get to be the size of a mule deer.
如果我们人类也有那种大小的差异
It we had that kind of size variation in humans,
我们会发现有些人就如奔走的芭比娃娃般
we would have people running around the size of Barbie dolls.
在那个时代
NARRATOR: In his day,
达尔文知道这一系列的大小不同不是偶然出现的
Darwin knew this range of sizes hadn't come about by chance.
而是经过小心翼翼的选择过程
Through a careful process of selection,
狗饲养员对各种不同性状的狗进行杂交
dog breeders mix different dogs
长生了新品种的狗
with different physical traits to create new forms.
达尔文认真思考他看到饲养员
Darwin was intrigued by what he was seeing
对这些狗所做的事
breeders doing with the domestic dog.
他们选择单个性征，例如大小或形状
They could select for individual traits like size or shape,
而它们会按着他们的想法而改变
and they could actually change their breed.
例如 Whippe
NARRTTOR: The Whippet,for example,
被驯服去追逐兔子
had been developed to chase rabbits.
它是由速度很快的灰狗
It was created by mixing greyhounds for speed,
和能狩猎的猎狗杂交而成
with terriers,used to hunt small game.
这触动了达尔文
And then it hit Darwin.
没有人类的干扰，
Was there a similar form of selection going on in nature,
自然也是有着相似的选择功能吗？
but without human interference?
自然的选择可以解释
Could natural selection
生物的多样性吗？
explain the great diversity of life?
卡罗尔：这太精彩了
CARROLL: It was brilliant.
他把一些熟悉的、习以为常的
He took something very familiar and comfortable,
例如，动物的生育
for example,animal breeding,
解释这个在自然中同样进行的事情
and explained that the same sort of thing was going on in nature
只是这是在没有人类指引下进行的，节奏也有点不同
just at a little bit different pace and with no human guide.
但是到底是什么对自然来进行选择呢？
NARRATOR: But what could be carrying out selection in the wild?
这使得达尔文用全新的眼光来重新彻底看待自然
It was then that Darwin took a completely fresh look at nature.
维多利亚时代关于自然的观点一直是令人信服的
The Victorian view of nature was sentimental.
那就是弱肉强食
Lambs lay down with lions.
但达尔文在贝格尔号的旅行中
But Darwin's travels on the Beagle
让他有了新的不同的观点
led him to a different view.
对达尔文而言，大自然是野蛮的
For Darwin,nature was savage.
每个生物都在为生存而挣扎
Every creature was locked in a desperate struggle for survival,
而最终都以死亡结局
ultimately ending in death.
自然界生物死亡的规模的惊人而可怕的
The scale of death in nature is absolutely horrendous.
有些时候不仅仅是死亡
And sometimes it's not just that there's a lot of death,
还是令人哀伤的死亡
but it's very unpleasant death.
但是在这残酷的混乱当中，达尔文看到了一个规律.
NARRATOR: But in all this brutal chaos,Darwin saw a pattern.
卡罗尔：达尔文揭示了自然界其实进行着一场战争
CARROLL: Darwin showed that nature was a battlefield
所有东西都在竞争
and that everything was in competition.
这残酷的自然界的战争
And this brutal battle,this war of nature
正如达尔文描述的，实际上是一个富有创造性的过程
as Darwin described it,was actually a creative process.
达尔文注意到的这个规律
NARRATOR: The pattern that Darwin saw
揭示了能够生存下来的生物都是最能适应
was that the creatures that survived were those best adapted
他们所居住的独特的环境
te the specific environments they lived in.
举个例子，有些生物要适应极端的气候
For instance,some could handle extremes of climate.
另外一些是出色的捕杀机器
Others were brilliantly honed killing machines,
非常擅长捕捉猎物
perfect for catching the available prey.
也有一些动物非常擅长
Still others were perfect
去避开那些可能的猎杀者
to evade those who might be hunting them.
但是这一关于大自然的残酷的观点
But how did this harsh view of nature
又是如何解释在加拉帕戈斯群岛上，
explain the finches on the Galapagos,
正如达尔文所见到的那样，不同岛上的雀
where Darwin observed that the birds on different islands
有不同形状的喙？
had different beak shapes?
不管怎样，这些不同的喙
Somehow,those different beaks
有助于这些雀类的生存
must be helping the finches survive.
塔宾：加拉帕格斯岛上的麻雀
TABIN: The finches of the Galapagos Islands
有不同形状和大小的嘴
have beaks of many sizes and shapes.
这是有理由的：
And there's a reason for that.
他们用嘴作为生存的工具
They use their beaks as tools.
想想看，有种强劲的工具
Now,if you think of the type of tool you would want
可以啄碎果实
to crush a seed that's very tough,
而果实又是你的所好
but is the food that you really like,
你也会想要一个嘴巴巴，
you'd want a beak like this,
而这种嘴正是地雀所拥有的
which is the type of beak the ground finch has.
在这个小岛上，唯一的食物的是种子，极难啄碎
On an island where the only food is seeds that are hard to crack,
而一张短小而强劲的嘴巴即意味着可以生存
a short,powerful beak will mean a finch will survive.
但是在其他的岛上
But on another island,
可以食用的东四不是果实，而是花朵
the available food isn't seeds but flowers.
如果你想进入狭窄的区域，
It you wanted to get into narrow spaces to get pollen and nectar
吮吸极难吸食的花粉和花蜜，
that are very hard to get at,
你需要的不是个巨大坚硬的嘴
you wouldn't need a big,strong beak,
而是个锐利的嘴
you'd need a probing beak.
所以，不同的岛上
NARRATOR: So,on a different island,
食物不尽相同，
where you have a different food source,
而鸟雀们也就有着不同的嘴
you have a different beak shape.
而这种现象在加拉帕格斯群岛上司空见惯.
And this pattern was repeated across the Galapagos.
这么看来，似乎雀喙
It seems that the finches' beaks
已经适应了不同岛屿的特殊食物类型
had altered to fit the diet of each particular island.
这也就是为什么最初的一种鸟雀
And that was how one original type of finch
而衍变为后来的多种鸟雀
had been transformed into many.
但是这些变化是如何产生的呢？
But how had these changes come about?
这不，达尔文又掌握了另外一条线索
here,Darwin had another clue.
这他在他自己的家族中也发现了这点
He could see it in his own family.
就像父辈们知道的
As every parent knows,
并没有两个孩子是完全一样的
no two children are ever exactly the same.
达尔文和他哥哥伊拉斯莫斯长得就不一样，
Charles looked different from his brother,Erasmus,
尽管他们父母一样
even though they shared the same parents.
达尔文的儿女们也看上去不像他和他妻子艾玛
Charles's children looked a bit like him and his wife Emma.
而且他们看起来都各不相同
But they too looked different from each other.
这意味着在他们身上有了某种变化
That was something he called variation.
他意识到并不是一个人出现这种情况
He realized that not every individual was the same,
这种情况 很常见
stamped out like a toy from a press.
但是确实有着不同
But there was variation.
达尔文意识到
NARRATOR: Darwin realized that variation
这种衍变一定是大自然产生变化的起点
must be the starting point for change in nature.
任何的物种，即使是寄生在垃圾里的生物，
In any generation,the animals in a litter
都各不相同
are never quite the same.
而在大自然，这种微小的不同
And in the wild,such a tiny variation
便意味着生与死
might make all the difference between life and death.
打个比方说，两只企鹅在脂肪厚度上，
Two penguins,for instance,might differ a tiny bit
也许会有细微差别
in the thickness of their blubber--
这对极寒生活可关键了
a big factor if you live in extreme cold.
在恶劣的气候中，环境会选择
In a harsh climate,the environment will select
谁能生存，而谁又将死去
who will live and who will die.
慢慢地，达尔文认为，经过很多代繁衍
And slowly,Darwin suggested,over many,many generations,
这种微小的衍变使得适者生存，
these tiny variations would allow the fit to get fitter
而不适者则湮灭在时间的洪流中
and the unfit would vanish.
这些变化一点点积累，
These variations accumulate
最终，新的物种便分开了
and eventually,new species branch off.
这就是物竞天择
This is evolution by natural selection.
这就是新物种诞生的其中一个关键因素
It is one of the keys to how new species are formed.
在肺结核困扰的八年时间里
Ank so,in 1859,after years of painstaking research,
达尔文终于发表了他的著作
Darwin finally published his masterwork,
--- 《物种起源》.
On the Origin of  Species.
任何赞誉之词都不为过
It is still impossible to overstate its importance.
这是一部真正意义上的划时代的的杰作
It was really a quantum advance in understanding.
它使人们为之一振，彻底颠覆了人们的观念
It shook people up,it changed the way people thought.
过去那种
NARRATOR: Gone was the idea that all species
所有物种都是完美而万古不易的
were created perfect and immutable,
人们曾作为信条的陈腐观点一去不复返了
taken as an article of faith.
在这基础上，达尔文提出了合理的
In its place,Darwin provided a proper scientific theory,
以观察事实为基础的科学理论
based on facts and observation.
这可比远远不止
It is much more than the presentation of simply
是简单的自然选择说
the idea of natural selection.
这是，这是一种对
It is a,it's a vision
自然选择是如何产生进化的绝妙猜想
of how evolution by natural selection works.
150年后，达尔文的理论经受住了时间的考验
150 years later,his theory has stood the test of time.
卡罗尔：达尔文观点是如此地准确无误，这真令人惊叹
CARR0LL: What's amazing is that Darwin got so much right.
达尔文的进化论基本上至今仍然不可撼动
His ideas largely stay intact today.
然而，达尔文自己
NARRATOR: But Darwin himself
也承认他的进化论还存在缺陷
acknowledged that there were holes in his theory.
他并不知道其作用机制
He didn't actually know how it worked.
他也不知道生物体内到底在发生着什么变化
What was happening inside a creature's body
使得生物产生变异？
that makes it change?
如今，现代科学通过揭示达尔文不曾想到的隐藏机制，
But now,at last,modern science is providing the answers
将对这一问题提供答案
through a hidden mechanism that Darwin knew nothing about
皮纳卡特沙漠，位于亚利桑那州，那儿环境恶劣而严酷
Arizona's Pinacarte Desert is a harsh and brutal place.
尤其是岩小囊鼠，更能体会到这点
Especially if you're a rock pocket mouse.
纳赫曼：这些老鼠就像是沙漠里的士力架巧克力
NACHMAN: They're the Snickers bar of the desert.
这可是真的，他们几乎成为所有生物的猎物
They really are,they're eaten by everything.
他们可能被狐狸或者土狼吃掉
They're probably eaten by foxes and coyotes
抑或是响尾蛇和猫头鹰
and rattlesnakes,owls.
岩小囊鼠只有半盎司重，
NARRATOR: Weighing just half an ounce,
这种老鼠在那些大型捕食者面前，简直是不堪一击.
this mouse could never fight off these large predators.
为了生存，最好的办法就是伪装
Its best hope for survival is camouflage.
不足为奇地
Not surprisingly,
岩小囊鼠的皮毛与皮纳卡特的岩石颜色类似，
its fur matches the color of the Pinacarte rocks.
然而，在沙漠的某些地方
But in some sections of the desert,
环境有所不同
the environment is different.
远古火山的喷发，
Ancient volcanoes erupted
使得如今的沙漠
and now the desert is a patchwork
布满了黑熔岩及浅色岩石
of dark lava and light rock.
显然，浅色皮毛的老鼠在黑熔岩上的话，很容易就成为猎物
But of course,a light mouse on a dark rock is easy pickings.
因此，有些事情发生了，也许达尔文也预料到了
So,something has happened that Darwin might have predicted.
生活在黑熔岩中的小鼠
The mice now living on the dark rocks
他们的皮毛已经进化成了深色
have evolved darker fur.
而那些生活在浅色岩石中的老鼠依然是毛发浅浅的
Those that stayed on the light rocks remain light.
迈克尔.纳赫曼被深深吸引住了
Michael Nachman was fascinated.
这是怎么发生的呢？
How had this happened?
为了找寻答案，他首先得逮些老鼠
To find out,he first needed to catch some mice.
因此，他和肖恩卡罗尔一起，
So,with Sean Carroll,
去查看他前一晚放置的捕鼠陷阱
he visits a line of traps he set the previous night.
纳赫曼：所有的黑毛老鼠的小腹都是白色的，
NACHMAN: All of the dark ones have a white underbelly
想必腹部黑色是不需要经过自然选择的吧，
and presumably,there's no selection for dark on the belly
因为那些捕食者多从上方捕杀老鼠
because predators are going,coming from above.
这个达尔文可能也做过
NARRATOR: This much Darwin could have done.
找到了一些老鼠，并将他们皮毛的颜色
Find some mice and compare the color of their fur
和周围环境相比较
to their environment.
而纳赫曼现在可以做点
But Nachman can now do something
达尔文从未做过的事儿
that Darwin never could.
他可以深入观察动物的DNA.
He can look inside the animal's DNA.
对DNA的研究是
The study of DNA is one
现代科学的一项伟大胜利
of the great triumphs of modern science.
它把我们对
It has taken our understanding
生物的进化和发展
of how creatures evolve and develop
引领到一个连达尔文从未想过的境地
to a level that Darwin could never have dreamed of.
卡罗尔：DNA分子是生命的真正秘密之一
CARROLL: The DNA molecule is one of the real secrets of life.
这是个完美的系统
It's a perfect system
储存了大量的控制所有生物必要组成
for storing the vast amounts of information
的遗传信息.
that's necessary for building all kinds of creatures.
DNA由一条长分子链组成
NARRATOR: DNA consists of one long molecule
以双螺旋式结构盘旋着
spiraling around in a double helix.
螺旋结构依次由四个碱基构成
That helix is,in turn,made up of four smaller molecules,
分别称为腺嘌呤A 鸟嘌呤G 胸腺嘧啶T 胞嘧啶C
called by the letters G,A,T and C.
在每个生物的细胞内都可以发现DNA的存在
DNA can be found in the cells of every living thing on earth.
贾德森：我认为DNA的惊人之处在于
JUDSON: The thing about DNA that I think is remarkable
其DNA分子本身，
is that the molecule itself is so elegant.
只是几个简单的碱基，
With a small number of letters,
却蕴涵着无穷的信息
you can say almost infinite words.
这才是关键所在
NARRATOR: And that is the key.
DNA 是人体内遗传密码，有两条链组成
DNA is a code and its double strand contains
这些信息组成了各种性状
all the information to make living things
决定生物的生长和发展
grow and develop.
DNA分子中分布着的是
Lined along each DNA molecule are ranged
组成基因的特殊序列.
special sequences of this code that form our genes.
而很多基因最终变成了蛋白质
Many genes get translated into proteins.
这些蛋白质构成了身体的基础
And these proteins make the stuff of our bodies.
其中一种构成了头发
One protein makes hair.
另外一种则构成软骨
Another makes cartilage.
还有的组成肌肉
Others make muscle.
卡罗尔：DNA 神奇之处在于
CARROLL: What makes DNA so amazing
它仅仅包含四种碱基，
is that it just contains four letters,
而这四种碱基的各种不同组合
but all sorts of combinations of those four letters
却包含了构成这个星球上所有生物
contains all the information for making
的所有信息
all the creatures that are on the planet.
某种基因决定了
NARRATOR: It's a gene that determines
我们的眼睛是蓝色的还是其他颜色
whether our eyes are blue or not.
其他一些基因使我们产生雀斑
Another gives us freckles.
另一些基因则让我们脸上出现酒窝
Another gives us dimples.
但是DNA 也有个非常重要的特征，
But DNA has one other vital quality.
它不会一成不变
It doesn't stay the same.
（哭泣声）
(crying)
孕育婴儿时，受精卵
When a baby is conceived,the fertilized egg receives
从母体和父体分别获得一半DNA
half its DNA from the mother and half from the father,
从而创造出一个全新的组合体
creating wholly new combinations.
这就是为什么孩子会跟双亲长相略有相似
It's why we look a bit like our parents,
却又不尽相同.
but also different.
另一种DNA产生变化的方式就是突变
Another way that DNA can change is mutation.
卡罗尔：突变是进化过程中的
CARROLL: Mutation is a critical ingredient
另一个关键因素
in the recipe for evolution.
没有突变的话，大自然的一切将保持一致性，
Without mutation,everything would stay constant
一代代相传
generation after generation.
而突变会产生变种，使得个体产生差异
Mutation generates variation,differences between individuals.
当细胞分裂及机体发育时，
NARRATOR: Mutations can happen as our DNA copies itself
DNA会自我复制，而突变也即在这个过程发生
when our cells divide and our bodies develop.
例如腺嘌呤A可能被鸟嘌呤G替代
An "A" for instance,can be replaced by a "G"
或者胞嘧啶C 变为胸腺嘧啶T
or a "C" by a"T."
这些都将导致不可预知的突变
This can cause minute changes that no one is even aware of.
在突变
But when mutations occur
在我们传给后代的细胞内发生微小变化时，
in the cells we pass down to our chindren,
却能引起机体产生极大的变化.
they can cause big changes.
就像使浅色老鼠颜色变深一样.
Like turning a light-colored mouse dark.
突变似乎意味着坏事的发生
"Mutation" seems to mean that something bad has happened.
而对机体而言，突变很难说是好的，还是坏的
Well,mutations are neither good or bad.
突变是否受欢迎，
Whether they are favored,
或遭到抗拒、抑或保持中立
or whether they are rejected,or whether they're just neutral
这主要由机体所处的条件决定
depends upon the conditions an organism finds itself.
对于小囊鼠来说，
So for the pocket mouse,
它产生了毛色变黑的突变.
a mutation that caused the mouse to turn black...
这对于生活在黑熔岩的老鼠来说，
That is good if you're living
是有益的
on black rock,it's bad if you're living
而对生活在沙质沙漠中的老鼠来说则是不好的
out in the sandy desert.
正是突变，
NARRATOR: It was that mutation,
使得浅色老鼠变黑，
the one that turned a light-colored mouse dark,
而这也正是纳赫曼所探寻的
that Michael Nachman was hunting for.
回到实验室后，他开始了艰辛的工作，
Back in the lab,he began the painstaking business
通过比较两种老鼠的基因
of comparing the genes of the two types of mice,
试图找出其中的差异.
trying to pinpoint any differences.
纳赫曼：当你真的不知道你会发现什么的时候，
NACHMAN: Science is fun
科学变得非常有趣
when you really don't know what you're going to find.
通过逐个检查两只老鼠的基因
NARRATOR: One by one the genes in the two nice
发现完全一样
proved identical.
但是同时，他在一个基因里发现了一些东西
But then,in one gene,he found something.
基因序列中，有四个地方
There were four places where the sequence
的“A”、“T”、“C”、和“G”不一样
of"A's," "f's," and "G's" were different..
当一只老鼠出生的时候就伴随着这些基因突变
When a mouse is born with these mutations,
它的毛就长成了黑色
its fur grows dark.
这个意味着它可以在黑色的岩石里生存下来
And that means it can survive on the dark rocks
而其他的并不可以存活
when others would not.
这就是一个很清楚的例子，证明了进化论
Here wes a clear example of evolution
和自然选择确实在发生作用
and natural selection at work.
我想达尔文应该会很高兴的
I think Darwin would have been delighted
如果他知道我们找到了这些基因
to know that we can find the genes
导致了进化的逐渐改变的话
that are responsible for evolutionary change.
这只是人们找到的基因突变和进化之间关系
NARRATOR: And this was just one of many links
中的其中一个
that have been found between genetic mutations and evolution.
科学家们现在可以很精确地
Scientists can now pinpoint
用行动来描述关于进化论的一连串例子
a range of examples of evolution in action.
疣猴可以辨认颜色
The Colobus monkey can see in color
这都是由于一个基因上的突变而引起的
because of a mutation in one gene.
它现在可以从一堆硬邦邦的绿色老叶子中
It can now tell nutritious red leaves
分辨出有营养的红色叶子
from tough,old green ones.
一个基因的小故障使得这些南极的鱼
A genetic glitch gave this Antarctic fish
血液有了强效的防冻剂
a potent antifreeze in its blood.
所以它可以在冰水里存活
So it can survive in the icy waters
而其他的鱼则不行.
when others cannot.
基因突变和进化之间的这种联系
So powerful was this link between
非常显然而强有力，而这也就引出了一种观点的形成
genetic mutation and evolution that an idea took hold.
即要想理解进化论是怎么发挥作用的，
To understand how evolution works,
你所需做的事情就是对比所有生物的基因
all you need to do is compare creatures' genes.
有人可能会认为要弄清楚所有的物种演变
One might think that you could understand all of evolution
只需要确定每种生物的基因位置即可
simgly by mapping the genes of every creature.
识别所有的基因，区分所有的区别
Identify all the genes,identify all the differences
然后就可以解释不同生物的千差万别了，例如
and you could explain the differences between,say,
老鼠、猴子和人类
mouse and monkeys and humans.
所以当人类基因组计划在1990年开始实施的时候
NARRATOR: So when the Human Genome Project began in 1999,
整个科学世界一片震动
the scientific world was on tenterhooks.
人类总共有三十多亿的DNA碱基序列
All three billion letters of our DNA
得陆续地鉴定
were going to be identified in order.
同时，有一些动物的DNA
In parallel,the DNA of some animals
和植物的也被拿来排序鉴定
and plants was also being sequenced.
显然，这对我们对不同的生命体是怎么进化来的这一方面的认知
Surely,this would be a quantum leap in our understanding
将会是一个巨大的突破
of how different life-forms evolved.
这又引出了另一观点：像我们人类一样的复杂的动物
With this came another idea: that complex animals like us
会比简单的动物具有更多的基因
would have many more genes than simpler ones.
而我们人类，则是这个星球上最复杂
Here we are,the most complex
和最精细的动物，对吧？
and sophisticated animal on the planet,right?
或许你会认为这个观点需要
You might think that would require
更多基因信息来证实
a whole lot more genetic information.
论断已经下了
NARRATOR: The betting was on.
只是我们人类的基因组相对于其他生命体来说到底有多大呢？
Just how big would our genome be compared to other life-forms?
据估计，人类有
There were estimates that humans would have
8万到12万个基因
between,let's say,80,000 and 120,000 genes.
所以当最终结果在2003年出来的时候，所有人都震惊了
NARRATOR: So when the final answer came in 2003,it was a shocker.
人类只有23000个基因 --- 就跟一只鸡所拥有的数量一模一样
23,000 genes--the same number as a chicken...
比一串玉米的数量
less than an ear of corn.
莱文：我的意思是，当发现人类的基因那么少的时候
LEVINE: I mean,people were freaked out
人们完全震惊了
by the relatively small number of genes.
人类基因组中，只有大概22000到23000个
It's down to something like 22,000 or 23,000
蛋白编码基因.
protein-coding genes in the human genome.
简单的线虫拥有大概相同的数量
The simple nematode worm has about that same number.
相对于人类的基因组而言，
And there are plants that have considerably more genes
也有一些植物有多得多的基因组
than the glorious human genome.
整个人类基因组计划似乎成为了
The whole human genome project has been
一次令人羞愧的尝试，
a humbling experience,as we've discovered
因为事实上，我们并未发现最先期望的
that,actually,it doesn't take as many genes
那么多组成人类的基因.
to make a human as we had all hoped.
这还不仅仅是说我们只拥有那么少的基因
NARRATOR: And it wasn't just that we had so few genes,
而问题是很多关键基因
but many of our key genes were identical
尽然和其他动物的完全一样.
to those of other animals.
这已然是个重大突破，
Huge though the breakthrough had been,
基因革命开启了
the genetic revolution had opened up
一系列全新谜题的探究
a whole new set of puzzles.
作为一个解开进化论原理这个谜底的方法
As a solution to the mystery of how evolution works,
基因和突变只是整个故事的一小部分
genes and their mutations were only part of the story.
其中肯定还有其他一些更难以捉摸的东西
There had to be something else more subtle
和更加神秘的东西.
and more mysterious going on.
卡罗尔：我们接下来需要解释的是
CARROLL: We have to explain then,
如何在一系列非常相似的基因中
How do you get all these differences
找出其中的区别.
if you have really similar sets of genes?
探索那些
NARRATOR: The quest to uncover
达尔文从来都不知道的发现又得从头再来了.
what Darwin never knew would have to start again.
最初的比较有意义的结论来自那些生命体
The first tantalizing clues would come from those life-forms
达尔文早已研究过了 --- 胚胎
that Darwin himself had studied: embryos.
看看这些胚胎
Look at these embryos.
在刚开始怀孕的日子里简直不可能去分辨
It is almost impossible to tell just days after conception
哪个是小鸡，哪个是海龟
which is the chicken,the turtle,
哪个是蝙蝠，以及哪个是人
the bat,the human.
他们看上去几乎一模一样
They look almost the same.
只有当他们长大了才变得清晰到底什么是什么
Only as they grow does it become clear which is which.
正如现在的科学家一样，达尔文疑惑的是
Darwin wondered,as scientists do today,
为什么他们可以在开始的时候这么相似
How could they start out so similar
而在最后却这么不同呢？
and end up so different?
莱文：在胚胎告诉我们的事情中
LEVINE: There is something profound
这里面肯定有意义深远的东西
about what the embryo was telling us.
而且我们已经再次发现达尔文到所说过的东西
And we have rediscovered what Darwin was talking about
胚胎是产生动物多样性
all along,that the embryo's  where the action is,
的关键所在
in terms of animal diversity,
胚胎是产生多样性的平台
it is the platform for diversity.
使现代生物学家觉深深着迷的
NARRATOR: What fascinates modern biologists
是所有这些不同的动物
is that all these different animals
尽管看上去不一样
don't just look the same,
却使用着几乎同样的关键基因
they are using virtually the same set of key genes
来塑造他们的躯体.
to build their bodies.
躯体决定基因控制着大脑的生长部位
The body plan genes determine where the head goes,
四肢的生长部位，以及它们会有什么样的外形
where the limbs go,and what form they take--
哪里是手臂
whether they are arms,
大腿或者翅膀.
legs or wings.
另外一组基因
Another set of genes
决定着动物的身体形态：
determines an animal's body patterning:
皮肤上的疹斑、条纹以及斑点.
the blotches,the stripes and spots.
都是同样的基因在所有的动物上起的作用
It is the same genes at work in every creature
从豹子到孔雀
from the leopard to the peacock
再到果蝇
to the fruit fly.
而且在它们身上产生了完全不同的结果
And yet they produce radically different results.
这使得科学家们在动物的身体是怎么变异的这一方面
This has led sciectists to a crucial insight
有了一个更深刻的理解
about how animal bodies have evolved.
不是由于基因的数量多少起作用
It's not the number of genes that counts.
卡罗尔：不是你所拥有的基因
CARROLL: It's not the genes you have,
而是你怎么使用这些基因，进而形成了
but how you use them that generates
动物王国的多样性
the great diversity of the animal kingdom.
找出这些同样的基因是怎么
NARRATOR: Finding out just how these same genes
用来创造这么令人吃惊的多样性的
are used to create such amazing diversity
这正是肖恩.卡罗尔以及
has been the work of Sean Carroll
不像一个现在科学的英雄---果蝇，
and an unlikely hero of modern science.
所从事的工作.
The fruit fly.
我非常想要到非洲草原上去研究那里的哺乳动物
As much as I'd like to study the mammals of the African Savannah,
它们比实验室里的动物拥有更少的选择
they make poor choices for laboratory animals.
他们体积庞大 昂贵同时它们繁殖得非常缓慢
They're large,expensive and they reproduce very slowly.
为了拿到数据，我们只有找最简单的例子
To get data,we have to find the simplest examples
这些例子跟我们想要了解现象相联系
to the phenomenon we want to understand.
但是这些卑微的果蝇却是一种不可思议
NARRATOR: But the humble fruit fly does weird
和有趣的东西
and wonderful things.
果蝇只为异性舞蹈
This fruit fly is dancing for sex.
一只全神贯注的母果蝇正在表演
A rapt female takes in the show.
她被公果蝇翅膀上的黑点
She's particularly besotted
深深吸引.
by the dark spots on the male's wings.
肖恩.卡罗尔也同样陶醉地看着他.
Watching it all is an equally besotted Sean Carroll.
卡罗尔：你可能觉得他们
CARROLL: You might think them
是有点令人讨厌，但是它们真的很迷人.
just be annoying,but they're really charming.
这个物种的公果蝇
And the males of this species
演出了一场精心设计的求爱舞蹈
does a rather elaborate courtship dance,
他在那些女性面前展示这些斑斓的翅膀
where he displays these spotted wings in front of the female.
对我们来说，它就像一只孔雀一样华丽
To us,it's as magnificent as what a peacock does.
但是果蝇的某些种系中
NARRATOR: But in some species of fruit fly,
公果蝇没有翅斑
the males don't have wing spots.
卡罗尔：这是另外一种果蝇
CARROLL: There's another fruit fly species
跟那些翅斑果蝇不一样
that's different from the spotted species
他们有两点不同：
in two important ways:
它的翅膀没有斑点
it doesn't have spots on its wings
它也不常会那么跳舞.
and it does a lot less dancing.
这，是一个经典的进化论谜题
NARRATOR: Here,then,is a classic evolutionary puzzle.
为什么有一种果蝇有翅斑而另外一种没有呢？
Why does one type of fly have spots and the other doesn't?
肖恩.卡罗尔想要弄明白
Sean Carroll wanted to know.
它们的基因发生了什么使得它们不一样呢？
What is going on in their genes that makes them different?
卡罗尔：所以我们想要使用
CARROLL: So we wanted to take apart
研究翅斑的基因机制
the genetic machinery for making wing spots
来弄明白到底这些翅斑是怎么进化的
to understand how those wing spots evolved.
卡罗尔开始了一个课程
NARRATOR: Carroll began the process of sifting through
这个课题是筛选果蝇的DNA
the two types of flies' DNA.
他有一条线索，使得他开始了他的研究
He had one clue to set him on his way.
他已经知道黑翅斑是怎样由基因编码成的
He already knew the gene that codes for the black wing spots.
他把它称作“画笔基因”
He calls it the"paintbrush gene."
但奇怪的是
But surprisingly,
当他比较两只果蝇的基因的时候
when he compared the genes of the two flies,
它们都有这个基因
they both had that gene.
但是，仅有一只果蝇有斑点
And yet,only one had spots.
卡罗尔：当我们观察这两种物种的基因的时候
CARROLL: When we look at that gene in the two species,
它们真的都有这种基因
really they both have this paintbrush gene.
所以差异在于
So the big difference
不是说它们有没有这个基因，而是它们是如何使用它
is not having the gene,it's how they use it.
其中一只在翅膀里使用它来长出斑点
One species uses it in the wing to make spots.
而另外一只没有
The other one doesn't .
然而为什么同种基因在一种果蝇上长出斑点
NARRATOR: So why did the paintbrush gene create spots in one type of fly,
却另一只没有？
but not in the other?
为了寻找答案
In search ot answers,
卡罗尔转而研究大家了解最少的DNA另一部分：
Carroll turned to one of the least understand regions of DNA:
一度被广泛认为是“垃圾”的
the vast stretches that were once known as"junk."
被称作基因组的暗物质
It has been called the dark matter of the genome.
神秘莫测的
Mysterious.
未可知的，
Uncharted.
奇奇怪怪的.
Strange.
双螺旋结构的大部分
The vast bulk of the double helix,
它有98%不会编码成蛋白质
some 98% of it,doesn't code for proteins,
而蛋白质是组成我们身体的主要物质
which make the stuff of our bodies.
而基因只占2%.
The genes which do,comprise just two percent.
甚至到现在也没有人可以确定
Even now,no one is sure
这些巨大的没有编码的区域实际起的大部分作用
what much of this huge non-coding area actually does,
但它长久以来就吸引着
but it has long beckoned
像肖恩.卡罗尔这样的基因突变探究者.
evolutionary detectives,like Sean Carroll.
这是一个弯管
So,this is a bend.
这些用来测试基因片段的？ 是的.
That's the fragment to test. Yeah.
卡罗尔已经发现斑点的基因本身
NARRATOR: Carroll had already learned that the paintbrush gene itself
在两种果蝇中是完全一样的
was identical in the two types of fly.
所以他深入研究果蝇的DNA.
So he extended his search through their DNA.
就在斑点基因的外面
And in one place,just outside the paintbrush gene,
他发现了一条重要的线索.
he found an important clue.
有个DNA的片段跟带翅斑果蝇
A stretch of DNA that was different
中的不一样.
in the fly with wing spots.
这意味着什么呢？
What could this mean?
所以卡罗尔进行了一次实验
So Carroll conducted an experiment.
他决定把带翅斑果蝇中
He decided to put that mysterious
找到的那个DNA片段
stretch of DNA that he had found in the spotted fly
植入不带翅斑的果蝇身上
in the unspotted fly.
为了弄清这个基因是否起作用
To help him see it it had any effect,
他把这以DNA片段和水母的一个基因连在一起
he attended it to a gene from a jellyfish,
这种基因能编码出使水母发光的蛋白质
a gene that codes for a protein that makes the jellyfish glow.
我们把这一DNA切成很小的片段
We cut the DNA up into little pieces,
然后我们把其中一些放到一个可以在黑暗中发光的蛋白质里
and we hook it up to a protein that glows in the dark.
然后再把这个植入不带翅斑的果蝇身上
And then we inject that into the unspotted fly.
接着，一些不寻常地事情发生了
NARRATOR: And then,something remarkable happened.
卡罗尔：当我们观察那些无翅斑的果蝇的时候
CARROLL: When me looked at those unspotted flies,
我们现在看到它们的翅膀在黑暗中发出一些斑点的光
we see now their wings are glowing in the dark with spots.
这些神秘的DNA的片段不知怎么的
NARRTOR: Somehow that mysterious stretch of DNA
已经启动了不带翅斑果蝇中的
had turned on the paintbrush gene
那些斑点基因.
in the unspotted fly's wings.
曾经不带翅斑，而今它拥有可以发光的翅斑.
Once spotless,now it had luminous spots.
卡罗尔：我们成功了！
CARROLL: Bingo.
我们已经发现这些起作用的DNA的片段
We'd found the piece of DNA that mattered.
卡罗尔已经发现了一些东西可以颠覆
NARRATOR: Carroll had found something that is revolutionizing
我们对动物体内基因突变
our understanding of how different
千变万化的认识
animal bodies have evolved.
有一小块称作“开关”的DNA
A piece of DNA called a "switch."
而这些开关并不是基因
Switches are not genes.
它们不形成像头发
They don't make stuff like hair,
骨头或者肌肉一样的物质
cartilage or muscle.
但是它们控制形成这些物质的基因的活动
But they turn on and off the genes that do.
卡罗尔开关是DNA很有威力的一部分
CARR0LL: Switches are very powerful parts of DNA,
因为它们允许动物在某些地方
because they allow animals to use genes
使用基因而在其他地方则不用，
in one place and not another,
在某个特定的时间点而不是其他时间点发挥作用，
at one time and not another.
形成翅斑，
And so,choreograph the spots
长出条纹和疹斑
and stripes and blotches of animal bodies.
在果蝇这个例子里
NARRATOR: In the case of the fruit fly,
这是一个基因突变
it's a mutation--
一个在DNA里极少的几个碱基的改变
a change in just a few letters of the DNA
这使得翅斑基因的开关打开了
that has caused the paintbrush gene to be switched on.
因此，一个带有翅斑的全新物种
Ang so,a whole new species with wing spots
诞生了.
has been created.
而如今，基因开关能解释的远远不止这些.
But switches are now explaining far more than that.
它们帮助解决了很多
They are helping to solve many
复杂的基因突变的难题
perplexing evolutionary questions.
就像一个物种
Like how one creature
失去了脚之后，
can become another creature
就变成了另外的物种.
by losing it legs.
这一切都回到了达尔文在蛇的胚胎里所发现的东西
It all goes back to what Darwin had seen in the snake embryo.
腿的雏形
The rudiments of leg bumps.
使他相信蛇肯定
This convinced him that a snake must have evolved
是从一些四脚动物基因突变而形成的
from some four-legged animal.
在这么多年以后 同样的谜题又被解决
Over the years that same mysterious process,
脚消失的现象同样在其他的生物上看到
the losing of legs,has been seen in other creatures.
比如说，鲸鱼
Like the whale.
它的前鳍
Its front flippers have all the bones
拥有陆地动物的手臂所拥有的所有骨骼
of a land creature's arm'
甚至连手指也有
even the fingers.
甚至是其躯体，
And further back in its body...
也有盆骨的痕迹
...it has the vestiges of a pelvis.
很显然 它来源于
Clearly,it is descended
陆地上的某种爬行动物
from an animal that walked on the land.
金斯利：有些动物
KINGSLEY: Lots of animals
进化成像蛇那样在陆地上滑行
have evolved to slither through the ground like snakes.
而有些动物则进化成像鲸鱼那样在水中
Other animals slither or swim through the water
滑行或游动
like whales.
因此 如果想要一副流线型的躯干
So if you need a streamlined body,
最好除去那些
it's good to get rid of these things
伸出躯干的部分 比如四肢等
that stick out from the body,like limbs.
正如鲸鱼一样
NARRATOR: Like the whale,
海牛是生活在海里的另一种巨型哺乳动物
the manatee is another huge mammal that lives in the sea.
同样地 它们的后腿也消失了
And it,too,has lost its hind legs.
怎样消失的呢
How?
达尔文永远无法回答这个问题
Darwin could never have answered that question.
而如今
But now,thanks to our understanding
有了对DNA开启和关闭的了解
of how DNA is switched on and off,
加上那条小刺鱼
and a very small fish,
我们正慢慢接近答案
we are getting a little closer.
这片湖 位于不列颠哥伦比亚省
In this lake in British Columbia,
有种生物本不应存在于此
there is a creature that really shouldn't be here.
它  就是刺鱼
A stickleback.
绝大多数刺鱼生活在海洋中
Most sticklebacks live in the ocean.
然而 大约1万年前
But some 10,000 years ago,
一些刺鱼搁浅于此湖
a few were left stranded in this lake,
从此与太平洋隔绝
cut off from the Pacific.
随着时间的推移 他们已经进化
And over the years,they have evolved.
在海刺鱼的
The ocean stickleback
肚皮上 有一双长得像长钉的
has a pair of fins on its belly
鱼鳍
that are like spikes.
这是起防御保护作用的
They are for defense.
他们长着这长钉一样的东西 吃起来可不容易
The spikes make the stickleback hard to eat.
然而 湖刺鱼
But the lake sticklebacks
肚皮上的鱼鳍却已经消失
have lost those spikes on their bellies.
正是这个 引起了
And it's this that intrigues researchers
研究员大卫.金斯利和他同事多尔夫的兴趣
David Kingsley and his colleague,Dolph Schluter.
为了揭开背后的秘密 他们首先找到了
To understand what's behind it,they first identified
决定鱼鳍的基因
the gene that makes the stickleback's spikes.
这是躯体关键基因中的一种 不出意外地
It's one of those key body plan genes and,not surprisingly,
他们发现海刺鱼和湖刺鱼体内
they found it to be identical in both
的这种基因别无二致
the ocean and the lake stickleback.
问题在于 为何这种基因在没有鱼鳍的湖刺鱼上
The question was,why hadn't in been turned on
并未被启动
in the lake stickleback,which had lost its spikes?
金斯利隐隐觉得答案就藏在基因开关中
Kingsley felt the answer might lie in a switch.
金斯利：我们知道存在这些基因开关
KINGSLEY: We know these genetic switches exist,
但仍然很难找到他们
but they're still very hard to find.
我们并没有所谓的基因密码
We don't have a genetic code
能让我们顺着DNA序列读着读着说，
that lets us read along the DNA sequence and say,
这儿有个基因开关  然后在这个特定的地方启动基因
There's a switch,to turn a gene on in a particular place.
终于 在并不编码成蛋白质的
NARRATOR: But eventually,hunting through the vast stretch of DNA
茫茫DNA中 他发现
that does not code for proteins,he found it.
湖刺鱼中的一个DNA序列已经突变
A section of DNA that had mutated in the lake stickleback.
这些突变意味着 基因开关已经被破坏
These mutations meant that the switch was broken.
能产生鱼鳍的基因并未被启动
It didn't turn on the gene that makes spikes.
这项工作的意义可能
But this work may have implications
不仅仅限于刺鱼
far beyond sticklebacks.
他们相信
They are convinced that there is a link
刺鱼鱼鳍的消失
between the stickleback losing its spikes
和海牛等其它生物腿的消失之间
and other creatures,like a manatee,
存在着某种关联
losing their legs.
有两条诱人的线索
And they have two tantalizing clues.
第一条线索是 决定刺鱼鱼鳍的
One--the same body plan gene
关键躯体基因
that is responsible for the stickleback spikes,
在后肢的进化中也扮演者同样的角色
also plays a role in the development of the hind limbs.
第二条线索则不如说是假说
The second clue is more tentative.
湖刺鱼的鱼鳍消失了
The lake stickleback may have lost its spikes,
而这一进化过程却留下了蛛丝马迹
but evolution has left behind some tiny remnants...
鱼刺的痕迹 随着进化 他们开始变得畸形，
the traces of bones,and they are lopsided--
左侧逐渐比右侧大
bigger on the left than on the right.
金斯利：我们想过 事实上
KINGSLEY: We thought,Wouldn't it be amazing
如果在不同动物体内
if in fact this classic unevenness is
相同的控制后肢消失的基因造成了
the signature of using the same gene
这种典型的不对称的话 这得多么令人惊奇啊
to control hind limb loss in an incredibly different animal?
因此 金斯利和他的团队开始研究海牛
NARRATOR: So Kingsley and his team went looking in manatees,
试图探寻这种畸形现象
searching for this lopsided pattern.
最终 他们有所发现
And they found it.
他们研究了整盒整盒的海牛骨架
In box after box of manatee skeletons,
发现海牛盆骨
they saw pelvic bones
左侧大 而右侧小
that were bigger on the left and smaller on the right.
目前 金斯利及他的团队正尝试
Right now,Kingsley and his team are looking
从海牛体内寻找
for the same switch in the manatee
类似刺鱼体内引起鱼鳍消失的基因开关
that caused the lake stickleback to lose its spikes.
如果他们找到了 这无疑将对解决那个困扰达尔文的问题
And if they find it,they will have a powerful explanation
提供巨大帮助
for something that baffled Darwin--
这个问题就是 为什么像海牛 鲸鱼和蛇等生物
how creatures like manatees,whales and snakes
能进化至双腿消失
can evolve away their legs.
然而 这又引出另一个问题
But all this begs another question:
既然这些基因开关在
If switches can play such a profound role
不同动物的不同形态中
in the different shapes and patterns of animal bodies--
比如翼斑 鱼鳍和后肢等发挥这至关重要的角色
from wing spots,to spikes to hind legs--
那一开始触动基因开关的又是什么呢
what is throwing those switches in the first place?
就像达尔文那样
Researchers would see the answer in animals
研究员们从加拉帕哥斯群岛中的地雀找到了答案
very familiar to Darwin-- those Galapagos finches.
Arkat和塔宾曾经花费很长时间
Arkat Abzhanov and Cliff Tabin have spent years trying
试图研究为何加拉帕哥斯的地雀
to find out exactly how those Galapagos finches
都有着不同的鸟喙
got their different beaks.
达尔文理论告诉他们
Their starting point was what they had learned
鸟喙对鸟的生存至关重要
from Darwin himself.
他们从这点出发开始研究
Their beaks were vital to the birds' survival.
在某个小岛上 地雀的主要食物是种子类果实
On an island where the main food was seeds,
他们的鸟喙长得短而硬 方便敲碎果实
finches had short,tough beaks for cracking them open.
而在另外一个小岛上 主要食物是花果类
On an island where the main food was from flowers,
这儿的地雀都长着长长的尖嘴 以便吮吸花蜜和花粉
birds had long pointy beaks for sunking up nectar and pollen.
同时 他们另有发现
And they knew something else.
雀鸟出生时 他们的嘴已经完全成形
The finches are born with their beaks fully formed.
因此 鸟喙形状各异的原因
So the answer to why they had
必定是在
such different beaks must lie in something
当雀鸟还在胚胎即鸟蛋中的时候 发生了什么
that happened te them as embryos in the egg.
塔宾：鸟蛋中
TABIN: Something amazing
正上演神奇
is happening inside those eggs.
不同的基因正或开启 或关闭
Genes are turning on and turning off.
而如何开启或关闭将决定
And depending on exactly how they turn on and off
将决定形成哪种雀鸟
will determine what type of finch is formed.
为了弄明刚刚发生的事情
NARRATOR: To find out just what was going on,
研究专家们首先得收集些鸟蛋
the researchers first had to collect some eggs.
悄悄地说 在这儿呢
(whispers): There she is.
她刚回来
She just came back. Yeah.
准备下蛋呢
To lay eggs.
看起来她得下好几个呢
It's really likely that she already has a clutch; great.
要出来了...
She's coming out.
看了下地雀鸟巢
NARRATOR: Abzhanov checks a ground finch nest
只发现一直鸟蛋
and finds a single egg.
他不能拿走这独个鸟蛋
He won't remove it,
因为鸟妈妈很可能会因此放弃这个鸟巢
because the mother might abandon the nest.
另外一个鸟巢已经生了三个鸟蛋了
Another nest already has three eggs.
他拿走其中一个用来研究
He takes one for his research,
他知道 鸟妈妈会再下一个鸟蛋替代拿走的
as he knows the mother will lay a replacement.
研究团队收集了好些
The team collects several eggs,
不同胚胎时期的鸟蛋
with embryos at different stages of development.
这样 他们就能清晰地画出
That way they will be able to chart exactly
不同鸟喙的发育过程
how the different beaks grow.
回到实验中 他们已经能够开始了
Back in the lab,they can begin the process.
这个仙人掌雀胚胎正很好地
This cactus finch embryo is well on the way
发育着它那标志性的又长又尖的喙
to its signature long,pointy beak.
而这只地雀胚胎也正发着它那又短又厚的喙
And this ground finch embryo is growing a short,thick beak.
我们想弄明白这些进化的基因
What we wanted to do was try and understand the genes
是怎么改变鸟喙
that were involved in making the beak the way it was--
变成成又大又厚的
making a big,broad thick beak different
而不是长而薄或者短而薄的
from a long,thin beak or a short,thin beak.
他们曾集中精力研究一组
NARRATOR: They concentrated on a group of genes
决定鸟类面部生长的基因
known to control the growth of birds' faces.
他们观察发现了一些有趣的事情
As they looked,they saw something intriguing.
一个特定的躯体控制基因
One particular body plan gene
于第五天在长短厚鸟喙
became active in the ground finch
的地雀体内变得活跃
with the short,thick beak,on the fifth day of development.
然而又过了24小时 这个基因却还是未能在
But it didn't go to work in the cactus finch
长着细长鸟喙的体内发生作用
with its long,slender beak for another 24 hours.
这给了我们启迪
This was a revelation.
在所有种类的鸟雀中 相同的基因决定着
The same genes were responsible for the beaks
不一样的鸟喙
in all types of finch.
而这些差异是由于 基因开启 时机和强度的不同
Any differences were in timing and intensity.
塔宾：我们搞明白了 我们彻底清楚了
TABIN: We've got it! We nailed it!
相同的基因决定着鸟喙的不同 或尖利
It's the same genes in making a sharp,pointy beak
或宽大 能啄碎坚果
or a big,broad nut-cracking beak.
而造成这些差异的关键在于
What's essential,what makes the difference,
你多大程度地开启了基因
and all the difference,is how much you turn the gene on,
又是何时开启或关闭它的
when you turn it on,when you turn it off.
这一发现带给我们的启示远非这些
NARRATOR: And the revelations didn't end there.
这一基因有些特殊
There was something special about this gene.
和所有的躯体控制基因并不会
Like all body plan genes,it doesn't actually
变成我们躯体的某部分那样
make the stuff of our bodies.
这一基因也没有变成这些鸟雀嘴巴的软骨
It didn't make the cartilage for the finches' beaks.
它只是启动基因开关
It throws switches.
基因开关随后开启或关闭
And the switches then turn on or off the genes
那些形成鸟喙的基因
that do make the beak.
卡罗尔：这些是不同类型的基因
CARROLL: These are a different type of gene.
他们控制着其他基因
They're genes that boss other genes around.
科学家们现在意识到 并非所有的基因都生而平等
Scientists now realize that not all genes are created equal.
一些基因成为我们躯体的一部分
Some make the stuff of our bodies.
而这就需要
And switches are needed
基因开关来开启或关闭这些所谓的 组织 基因
to turn many of these "stuff" genes on and off.
正是躯体控制基因开启了这些基因开关
The body plan genes are what throw these switches,
决定着 组织 基因何时做何事
which tell the stuff genes what to do and when.
这些微妙的安排将对
This subtle choreography can have profound effects
不同动物躯体的形成产生深刻的影响
on how different animal bodies are formed.
这一知识正帮我们解答
And this knowledge is helping us solve
或许是达尔文之谜中最难的谜题
perhaps the biggest Darwinian puzzle of all:
巨大的变化之谜
the mystery of the great transformations.
这一切得追溯到达尔文对生命之树的看法
It all goes back to Darwin's idea of the tree of life.
他认为 所有的生命形式最终都是互相关联的
That all life-forms are ultimately related.
源自最初的共同祖先 经过数十亿年之后
And from the earliest common ancestor over billions of years,
他们发生着改变 并呈现出多样性
they have changed and diversified
因此 所有的生物都从最初的看似相同
so that creatures that started out looking the same
逐渐进化成了后来的完全不一样
evolved to become completely different.
科学家们发现了很多令人惊异的关联
And scientists have made some amazing connections.
比如恐龙和鸟类拥有相同的祖先
That dinosaurs share a common ancestor with birds.
再比如鱼类很可能是
And that a fish must have been the ancestor
所有四肢动物的祖先 甚至包括人类
of all four-limbed creatures--even us.
达尔文的所有观点中 这个可能
Of all his ideas,this was probably
是其中最惊人的一个
Darwin's most astonishing.
卡罗尔：搞清楚
CARROLL: It was one thing to grasp
两种鸟雀为何不同和
how two species of finch could become different,
他们的鸟喙是怎么变化的是一回事
how their beak shape could change.
这只是一小步而已
That was a small step.
然而 那些巨大的差异呢
But what about the big differences?
比如游于海中的鱼
The differences,say,between the fish that swim in the sea
和行于陆地的动物呢
and the animals that walk on land?
这些差异又是如何发生的呢
How did those changes take place?
多年来
NARRATOR: Over the years,
发生这些巨大差异的证据已被找到
evidence for these great transformations has been found.
比如说 达尔文发表
For instance,just a year after Darwin published
《物种起源》仅仅一年以后
On the Origin of Species,
一种被称为“始祖鸟”的化石被发现
a fossil called "archaeopteryx" was discovered.
上面有着鸟和恐龙的特征
It had features of both birds and dinosaurs.
达尔文在胚胎中找到了同样有说服力的证据
And Darwin had seen equally persuasive evidence in embryos.
在所有陆地生物甚至包括人类中
Those slits in the ear of all land creatures,even humans.
那些耳朵中的狭缝在人类中变成内耳中的幼骨
In us,they become tiny bones in the inner ear.
而在鱼类中 他们则变成鱼鳃
But in fish,they become gills.
这暗示着陆地动物
A tantalizing hint that land animals
都是鱼的后裔
must be descended from fish.
然而 鱼是如何长出肢干并能在陆地上行走这一问题
But the stumbling block has always been how.
一直阻碍着我们
How could a fish develop legs and walk on land?
达尔文毫无头绪
Darwin had no idea.
而舒本决定啃这块硬骨头
But Neil Shubin was determined to tackle that problem.
舒本：这让我浮想联翩
SHUBIN: It captured my imagination.
看 这是鱼翅 而另一方面则是肢干
I mean,here's a fin and on the other side was a limb.
他们看起来是如此地不同
And they looked different in many ways.
我就想 这真是个值得我全身心投入的
And I thought,"Well,what a first-class scientific problem
科学难题之最
to devote my research to."
实际上 我已经致力于此项研究
And I've been devoting pretty much
超过20年了
my research to it ever since,over 20 years.
舒本研究的第一步是找到一颗化石
NARRTTOR: The hrst stage Shubin's quest was to find a fossil.
如果从某种意义上说 达尔文是正确的
If Darwin were right,somewhere out there,
那么一定有个过渡形式
there had to be a transitional form,
一颗拥有肢干雏形的鱼化石
a fossil that was part fish,but had the beginning of legs.
但问题是 去哪儿找呢
But where to look?
他想到了一个办法
He had one clue.
化石记录表明 有腿生物
The fossil record shows that creatures with legs
首先出现于大约3亿6500万年前
first appeared some 365 million years ago.
而在那之前 只有鱼类
Before that,they were only fish.
因此 年复一年 舒本
So,summer after summer,Shubin set up camp
在离北极仅有几百英里的
on Ellesmere Island,just a few hundred miles
埃尔斯米尔岛上安营扎寨
from the North Pole.
这儿散落着这一关键过渡时期的岩石
It has exposed rock from that crucial transitional time.
从科学家们拍的视频可以看出
The scientist's own video shows
这儿是多么地偏远 多么地荒凉
how remote and bleak the place was.
舒本：这儿天气寒冷
SHUBIN: It's cold.
整个夏天几乎都结冰
It's about freezing every day over the summer.
风很猛烈
Winds are high.
风速可以达到50英里每小时
They can get up to 50 miles an hour.
这儿还有北极熊出没
There are polar bears there.
我们不得不携带者枪支防身
We have to prepare ourselves by carrying guns.
这是个美丽的地方 你必须得爱她
It's a beautiful place. You've got to love it.
这儿是我的夏日之家
It's my summer home.
每一次远征的代价都及其高昂 三次
NAREATOR: Each expedition was costly,but after three of them
就足以证明他们的决心有多大
there was little to show for their efforts.
因此第四次远征就显得毫无意义了
A fourth trip seemed pointless.
舒本：我记得跟我同事的一次谈话
SHUBIN: I remember having a conversation with my colleagues saying,
你说 我们真的该去吗 花费真的很高吗
Well,should we go? Is this really a waste of money?
这是一次至关重要的时刻
This was our do-or-die moment.
我们几乎没去成
And we almost didn't go.
他们决定再去最后一次
NARRATOR: But they decided to try one last time.
三天以后 他们依然一无所获
After three days,they still hadn't found anything.
然后 当大家都心灰意冷时...
Then,just when no one was expecting anything to happen...
其中一名同事正在敲石头
A colleague was cracking rocks
那时我正离他五英尺
and I was working about five feet from him.
然后 我听到 嘿 嘿 伙计们 这是什么
And I hear,"Hey! Hey,guys,what's this?"
探出石头外面的是个鱼头
Sticking out of the cliff was the snout of fish.
这可不是一般的鱼 这可是条平头鱼
And not just any fish,a fish with a flat head.
看到这条
By seeing a flat-headed fish
大约3亿7500万年前岩石中的平头鱼
in rocks about 375 million years old...
我们都意识到终于找到了我们一直想要的
we knew we had found what we were looking for.
一只扁平的鱼头 眼睛向上凝视着
NARRATOR: A flat snout with upward staring eyes--
它拼命
the signature of an animal
想把头探出水面
that pushes its head out of the water.
因此 它需要借助其它东西比如四肢来探出水面
And for that,it would have needed something like arms.
舒本：我们顿时蹦蹦跳跳 互相击掌庆祝
SHUBIN: What we did at that moment was all jump around high-fiving.
那时 整个现场只有我们六个
It was,uh,you know,there were only six of us
场面很壮观
in the field that time,so it was quite a scene.
回来后 舒本和他的团队继续工作
NARRATOR: Back at home,Shubin and his team got to work,
开始化验那颗拥有3亿7500万年历史的化石
examining their 375-million-year-old fossil.
他们把这个新发现的鱼叫做“提克塔利”鱼
They named their new finding "Tiktaalik,"
这在因纽特语中指淡水鱼
an Inuit word for a freshwater fish.
提克塔利鱼是个完美的过渡产物
Tiktaalik is a perfect transitional form.
它大部分长得像鱼
Much of its body is that of a fish.
有鱼鳞
It's covered in scales.
但同时它也有些非鱼的特征
But it also had something very un-fishlike...
比如它长着手臂状的鱼鳍 或者说鱼鳍状的手臂
an arm-like fin,or perhaps a fin-like arm.
提克塔利鱼有着所有四肢动物
Tiktaalik had the bone structure that is seen
所拥有的骨骼结构
in the arms and legs of every four-limbed animal.
上面有块骨头 比较大
One big bone at the top,
下面有两块骨头
two bones underneath,
这使得腕部和踝部有一些骨头群
leading to a cluster of bones in the wrist and ankle.
这些所有的生物从
It's the same pattern that is found in everything
羊到牧羊犬 甚至到舒本本身 都有着同样的结构
from sheep,to sheepdogs,to Shubin himself.
现在我们找到了一种动物
You now have an animal
它能从底部冒出来
that can push itself up off the substrate,
不管是在水底 还是陆地上
either on the water bottom or on land.
问题显而易见
NARRATOR: One obvious question was:
为何提克塔利进化成这样的新结构呢
Why had Tiktaalik evolved this new structure?
就在它附近发现的另外一颗化石可能能回答这一问题
One possible answer is suggested by other fossils found near it.
有些大型捕食性鱼类
There are large predatory fish
大约10至15英尺长 和提克塔利鱼生活在一起
about ten to 15 feet long living alongside Tiktaalik.
提克塔利鱼成为了猎物
NARRATOR: Tiktaalik was prey.
为了生存下去 它们没多少选择
To survive,it had few choices.
要么长得大一点 要么长得坚硬一点
You can get big,you can get armor
或者 要么选择离开
or you can get out of the way.
舒本 认为提克塔利鱼选择了离开
NARRATOR: Shubin thinks Tiktaalik got out of the way.
用那些臂状的鱼鳍它们拼命
With those arm-like fins,it could have dragged itself
往陆地或浅滩逃
to safety on land or in the shallows.
但这仅仅解释了问题的一半
But this was only half the answer.
这并未揭示基因的真正机制
What it doesn't show us is the actual genetic mechanism,
即如何把决定鱼鳍的基因变成
the genetic recipe that builds a fin
决定肢干的基因的
into that which builds a limb.
经历了3亿7500万年之后
NARRATOR: At 375 million years old,
提克塔利鱼的DNA早已消失不见
Tiktaalik's DNA had vanished long ago.
因此 舒本需要
Shubin needed a next-of-kin,
另外和鱼相关的仍存活的同类
a fish relative that was still alive.
舒本：我们需要的是
SHUBIN: What we needed was a creature
在进化树中处于正确位置的一种生物
that was in the right part of the evolutionary tree,
它得是拥有非常肉质鱼鳍的鱼
but also a fish that has a very fleshy fin.
于是 他们继续搜寻
So the search was on.
有好几种鱼符合条件
NARRATOR: A number of fish fit the bill.
而 舒宾 唯独选择了一种...
But Shubin favored one in particular...
白鲟
the paddlefish.
舒本：白鲟可谓是非常奇怪
SHUBIN: The paddlefish is a really weird fish.
他们已经长出了很长的鼻子
They developed this really long snout.
并且非常贪食
And they're really voracious.
他们甚至相食对方
They eat each other.
因此 当他们游在一起的时候
So oftentimes you'll lose a lot of your fish
你会发现逐渐少了一些 因为他们互相吞掉对方
when they swim together,because they'll eat each other.
密西西比河的浅滩中的生物
NARRATOR: Living in the shallow waters of the Mississippi,
真可称得上是活化石
it's also a living fossil.
科学家们花了好些年 试图弄清
Scientists have spent years working out the relationships
不同鱼类之间的关系
between different species of fish
他们发现白鲟
and they know that the paddlefish
是和提克塔利鱼属于同种鱼类
is one of the last survivors
的仅有幸存者之一
of the class to which Tiktaalik once belonged.
然而 不像提克塔利鱼那样
But unlike Tiktaalik,
白鲟数量众多
the paddlefish is in plentiful supply.
白鲟是鱼子酱的一种常见来源
Paddlefish is a common source for caviar.
因此我们通常从鱼子酱农场得到白鲟
So we'd get our paddlefish from caviar farms.
有趣的是 虽然提克塔利鱼濒临灭绝
NARRATOR: Intriguingly,even though Tiktaalik is extinct,
但实际上白鲟才是更原始的种族
the paddlefish is actually the more primitive form.
跟提克塔利鱼比起来 白鲟的鱼鳍
Its fins bear far less relation
与臂或者腿关系不如那么密切
to an arm or leg than Tiktaalik's .
由于白鲟和提克塔利鱼息息相关
And because they are related,
这两种鱼应该拥有相同的基因
the two kinds of fish should share the same genes.
于是，舒本开始研究白鲟胚胎
So Shubin began looking at paddlefish embryos,
试图找寻决定鱼鳍的基因
hunting for the genes that built its fins.
很快 他锁定了一组特定的名为
And soon he zeroed in on one particular group
Hox的基因组
of body plan genes called Hox genes.
几乎在所有的稍微复杂的动物中 都能找到Hox基因
Hox genes have been found in all complex animals
从大约6亿年前的天鹅绒虫
from the velvet worm,that dates back some 600 million years,
到现代人类 都可以找到
to the modern human.
并且从始至终 他们的DNA序列
And in all that time,the letters of their DNA
都几乎保持不变
have remained virtually unchanged.
他们是基因群中的贵族
They are aristocrats of the gene community,
非常接近权利链的顶端
near the very top of the chain of command.
他们通过发育中的胚胎发号施令
They give orders that cascade through a developing embryo...
能激活发育成躯体的
activating entire networks of switches and genes
整个基因开关网
that make the parts of the body.
他们对生物的发育起着
They are absolutely critical to the shape and form
至关重要的作用
of a developing creature.
卡罗尔：这些基因决定着
CARROLL: These genes determine where the front
动物的前部和后部长成什么样
and the back et the animal's going te be--
顶部 底部 左边 右边
the top,the bottom,the left,right,
内部 外部分别长成如何 眼睛该长在何处
the inside,the outside-where the eyes are going to be,
腿该长在哪里 肠道又该长在哪里
where the legs are going to be,where the gut's going to be--
能长几个手指
how many fingers they're going to have.
舒本发现 Hox基因在白鲟鳍的形成过程中
NARRATOR: Shubin found that Hox genes had a key role
起着关键的作用
in the formation of paddlefish fins.
其中一组Hox基因控制着
One set of Hox genes orders
鱼鳍发育的第一阶段
the first stage of fin development--
这期间 白鲟躯干长出了一块坚硬的软骨
a sturdy piece of cartilage that grows out from the torso.
令人惊讶的是 在所有的包括人类的所有四肢动物中
Amazingly,in all four-limbed animals,even us.
完全相同的基因决定着长长的上臂骨的生长
Exactly the same genes create the long upper arm bone.
在白鲟中 另一Hox基因组
In the paddlefish,another set of Hox genes
控制鱼鳍生长的下一阶段
command the next stage of fin development.
同样地 又是完全一样的基因
Again,exactly the same genes
控制我们前臂骨骼的生长
control the growth of our two forearm bones.
最终 相同的基因以不同的顺序
Finally,the same genes,working in a different order,
决定着鱼鳍的末端骨头
make the array of bones at the end of the fin.
而又是相同的基因以同样的顺序
The same sequence of the same genes
组成了我们手指和脚趾
makes our fingers and toes.
这可是个重大发现
This was a massive revelation.
瞬间地 所有有肢动物的起源
Suddenly the origin of creatures with arms and legs
看起来似乎并不存在巨大差异
didn't seem such a huge leap after all.
如果提克塔利鱼中也存在同样基因发挥作用的话
It the same genes were at work in Tiktaalik,
那么史前鱼类就应该已经携带了好些能控制肢干
then many of the genes needed to make legs and arms
生长的这些基因
were already being carried around by prehistoric fish.
只需要几次突变
All it needed was a few mutations--
关于基因开关
a few changes to the timing and order
何时开关的突变
of what was turned off and on,
鱼鳍便能变成肢干
and a fin could become a limb.
舒本：通常情况下 进化过程中 基因全新结构的起源
SHUBIN: Oftentimes the origin of whole new structures in evolution
并不涉及新基因的来源或
doesn't involve the origin of new genes
整个全新基因图谱
or whole new genetic recipes.
那些老的基因经过重新配置
Old genes,old genetic pathways can be reconfigured
产生了全新的美妙事物
to make marvelously wonderful new things.
因此 现在达尔文无法解答的问题有了可能的答案
NARRATOR: So it is now possible to answer what Darwin didn't know
我们亦能解释为何四肢动物
and explain how all four-legged creatures
很可能起源于鱼类了
could be descended from fish.
在大约3亿7500万年前
Around 375 million years ago,
像提克塔利鱼那类生物收到攻击
a creature like Tiktaalik was under attack...
遭遇捕食者的掠杀
harried by predators.
然而一些Hox基因的随机变化
But some random changes to the activity of the Hox genes
使得他们的鱼鳍逐渐变成肢干
led to its fins,developing a structure like a limb.
接着 提克塔利鱼能逃离险境 成功着陆了
Tiktaalik could now haul itself out of danger,onto dry land.
在陆地上 它会发现一个植物丛生 昆虫遍地的世界...
On land,it would have found a world of plants and insects...
一个等待征服的世界......
a world ripe for colonization...
一个属于有肢动物的世界
a world perfect for animals with arms and legs.
再之后 又经过了数百万年
And so,over millions of years,
它们长出来的肢干继续进化 变得丰富多彩
these new limbs evolved,changed and diversified.
有的奔跑
Some became adapted for running.
有的飞翔
Others for flying.
有的能挖洞
Some for digging.
而有的会旋转
Others for swinging.
就这样 四肢动物以各种方式
And so four-limbed creatures took over the world
占领了这个世界
in a multitude of different ways.
而这 都源于当初一些古老基因组的变化
And all because of some changes to an ancient set of genes.
这也正是
And this is the true wonder
我们对DNA的新认识告诉我们的
of where our new understanding of DNA has led us to.
存在着组成我们躯体的基因
There are genes that make the stuff of our bodies,
也存在着控制这些基因开闭的基因开关
switches that turn them off and on,
以及控制这些基因开关的其他基因
and still other genes that give those switches orders.
加上复杂的 基因开关开启和关闭 时机和强度
Together in a complex cascade of timing and intensity,
他们一起产生了这个星球上
they combine to produce the amazing diversity
的万事万物
of life on this planet.
这 真是达尔文所闻所未闻的
That truly is something that Darwin never knew.
然而 这一新科学能解释
But can this new science also explain
人类从何处来 这个或许是
perhaps the most fundamental question of all?
最根本的问题吗
What makes us human?
人类的活动范围实在是令人惊叹
The scope of human activity is simply astounding.
我对人类的一切疯狂行为
What fascinated me were
极其感兴趣
all the crazy things that humans do.
瞧瞧周围
You look around the world,
如果你发现有什么奇怪或者是有趣
and if there is something bizarre and interesting
的事儿好玩儿的话
that you could be doing,
说不定世界上其他地方的人类也在玩
humans are up to it somewhere in the world.
当你看到这所有的一切时
And when you look at all of this,
你只需要自问一句 人类为何如此特别
you just have to ask yourself,what makes us special?
人类的本源又是什么
What is the basis for this humanness?
对于自然的所有鬼斧神工来说
NARRATOR: For all nature's wonders,
人类取得的成就可谓独一无二
the achievements of the human mind are truly unique.
我们是唯一
We are the only species
会思考其他物种会怎么看待人类的物种
to think about what others think about us,
会惩罚我们的侵害之物
to punish those who have harmed others,
会创造艺术...
to create art...
音乐...
music...
建筑...
architecture...
从事科学研究...
to engage in science...
医学研究...
medicine...
会开发微芯片
the microchip.
只有我们 能举手之间摧毁数百万的生命
Only we can destroy millions at the push of a button.
毫不奇怪地 一直以来 我们都认为
Hardly surprising,then,that for centuries we thought
人类和其他一切物种都不一样
that humans were different from all other species,
我们是照着神的样子所造 更为高等
better,created in the image of God.
然而 后来达尔文
But then Darwin began to draw conclusions from evidence
根据人类胚胎中的鳃裂得出结论
like gill slits in human embryos
人类起源于鱼类
that showed that we were descended from fish.
人群惊叫
(people exclaim)
但当提到其它近亲物种时
But it was when he drew parallels with other
达尔文陷入了麻烦
close relatives that he got into real trouble.
卡罗尔：达尔文结束航程返回伦敦后不久
CARROLL: Shortly after Darwin returned from his voyage,in London,
一只名叫“珍妮”的猩猩开始展出
an orangutan named Jenny went on exhibit.
这引起了巨大的轰动
And this was a huge sensation.
这是被关着展出的第一支猩猩
This was the first great ape to be exhibited in captivity.
达尔文被这只猩猩的
And Darwin was absolutely taken
童真般的天性深深吸引
with how she was sort of childlike in her ways.
同时 他发现这只猩猩
And he saw a lot of human behavior
和诸多人类行为及其相似
in the way this orangutan behaved.
达尔文认为
NARRATOR: When Darwin suggested
实际上 人类应该是来源于类人猿
that human beings must actually be descended from apes,
他因此遭受了猛烈抨击
he was savaged.
他被指控为攻击当时的核心信念
He was accused of attacking that core belief
即上帝创造了
that humankind had been created in the image of God
高于一切生物的人类
above all other creatures.
如今 我们和类人猿祖先一样这一理论
But today the idea that we share a common ancestor with apes
在生物学上已被广泛接受
is completely accepted in biology.
然而 把人类和类人猿的基因组排序后
Instead,as a result of having sequenced the genomes
麻烦来了
of both humans and apes,we face a very different puzzle.
凯蒂 波拉德 是黑猩猩DNA方面的专家
Katie Pollard is an expert on chimp DNA.
鉴于人类和黑猩猩之间存在着明显差异
Given all the obvious differences between humans
你可能会觉得两者之间的DNA应该迥异
and chimps,you might expect our DNA to be really different.
然而 事实上 两者近似度可以达到99%
But in fact,it's more like 99% identical.
人类和黑猩猩的DNA仅仅存在1%的差异
NARRATOR: Just a one-percent difference in the DNA of humans and chimps.
现代科学面临的谜题并非是
The mystery facing modern science is
如此不同的动物间怎么可能密切相关
not how can such different animals be related,
而是 关系如此紧密的动物会如此地不同
but how can such closely related species be so different?
而这是达尔文从来不明白的
That really is something that Darwin never knew,
科学家们逐渐找到了答案
but slowly,scientists are starting to find the answers.
他们首先从研究人类的一个关键器官
And one answer begins with insights into the genetics
手 找到了答案
of a key human organ,our hands.
人类的手真是一大奇迹 它敏捷而灵巧
The human hand is a marvel,nimble and dexterous.
大自然中从未出现过像这样的东西
Nothing quite like it exists anywhere else in nature.
手给与了我们
It offers us a unique combination
精度和力量的独特组合
of precision and power,
而这都在拇指上完美体现
and much of that is down to one particular digit,our thumb.
人类的手特征之一便是
One of the features of the human hand is our ability
我们能用拇指碰触到其他四个手指
to touch all four fingers with the thumb.
这使得我们可以像这样抓握
And that allows us to make grips like this,
非常好把握精确度
gives us a lot of precision.
强力抓握体现了使很大劲
The power grip is the ability to put a lot of strength
这样抓的能力
into this soft of contact.
因此 你拿着球的时候 你主要是在捏它
So if you're holding a ball,you're basically pinching it,
并可以使劲捏
and we can put a lot of strength into that.
最好抛个快球试试
NARRATOR: The better to throw a fastball with.
以便找出跟人类最接近的物种相比
Finding out why we have such versatile hands
为何我们拥有如此灵巧的手
compared to our nearest relatives is the task
这是耶鲁大学 吉姆 努南 的主要工作
of Jim Noonan at Yale University.
他开始筛选那人类与黑猩猩
He began sifting through that vital one percent of DNA
存在差异的1%的DNA
that is different in humans from chimps.
努南：科学上一个很基本的问题就是
NOONAN: It's kind of one of the fundamental questions
是什么让我们与众不同
in science is: What makes us who we are?
真的 这正是我们试图弄明白的
An that's really what we're trying to get to;
是什么使得人类之所以成为人类
what makes humans human.
这是一项缓慢的工作
NARRATOR: It was slow work.
1%听起来不太多
One percent may not sound like much,
但就这1%的DNA就包含着大约3000万个DNA的化学碱基
but it's still some 30 million of DNA's chemical letters--
A  T  C 和 G
A's,T's,C's and G's .
努南：基因组可是个大块头
NOONAN: The genome's a big place.
而且大多数情况下 稍微看看这些DNA序列 你真的无法判断，
And just by looking at sequence,you really can't tell,
哪段重要 哪段不重要
for the most part,what is important and what isn't .
他最终还是在人类DNA中有所发现
NARRATOR: But eventually,in human DNA he spotted something.
跟黑猩猩DNA相比 有段序列中有13处不同
A sequence that was different in 13 places compared to chimp DNA.
麻烦的是 他并不知道
The trouble was,he had no idea
这段DNA起着什么作用
what this piece of DNA actually did.
为了找到答案 他把这一DNA序列植入老鼠胚胎
To find out,he inserted it into the embryo of a mouse.
为了便于追踪这段DNA产生的效应
To make the effects of the DNA easier to follow,
他把这段基因和另外一个能散发蓝光的基因连在一起
he attached it to another gene that gives off a blue color.
这样的话 他就能看到
That way he could see
这段基因在胚胎的什么位置发生作用
where the gene became active in the embryo.
随着胚胎的发育 这段基因似乎
As the embryo develeped,the piece of DNA seemed te be active
无处不在地发挥着作用
all over the place.
而最有趣的是
But most intriguingly,
它在发育中的鼠爪中做着什么
it was doing something in the growing paw.
我想  这太棒了
Well,I thought "Wow,this is really cool."
这场面很是引人注目
It was a really striking image.
努南看到的是人类DNA在
NARRATOR: What Noonan saw was that the human DNA become active
老鼠的拇指和大脚趾中发挥作用
in the mouse embryo's thumb and big toe.
努南似乎找到了那个
It seems that Noonan may have found a switch
帮助我们长出那个部位
that helps form that key human attribute:
那个给予我们
our thumb,
力量和精确度的大拇指   基因开关
the part of our hand that gives us so much power and precision.
正是这种力量和精确度使得我们
It's that power and precision that enables us
能手持画笔...
to hold a paintbrush...
能操作工具...
manipulate tools...
能驾驶战斗机 能记录我们的思想
pilot a jet fighter,record our thoughts.
所有的这一些都使得人类和猿类并不相同
All those things that separate us from other apes.
当然 拥有大拇指是一回事
Of course,having a nimble hand is one thing,
而懂得如何使用大拇指又是另一回事了
but you have to know how to use it.
因此 你需要
And for that,you need to have
人类的另外一个标志性器官
humankind's other signature organ:
大脑
our brain.
人类的大脑大极了
The human brain is vast,
比黑猩猩大三倍
three times bigger than a chimp's ,
并且结构完全不一样
and is structured very differently.
弄清楚这一非同寻常的器官是如何进化的
How this extraordinary organ evolved is central
对理解人类为何以这种方式存在至关重要
to understanding why we are the way we are.
达尔文对这点也无法解释
It is something that Darwin himself was at a loss
这也正是为什么很多评论家无法接受
to explain,which is why many of his critics remained unconvinced
他的人类起源学说
by his account of human origins.
如今 为何我们拥有这么了不起的大脑
But now part of the answer to why we have
这一问题的答案可能来得很意外
such a remarkable brain may have come from a surprising source.
汉塞尔 斯特德曼 是一名专业的运动员
Hansell Stedman is a dedicated athlete
同时也是一名医生
and a medical doctor.
他从未想过他能为
He never imagined he would come up with an answer
这一进化史上的谜题提供答案
to a profound evolutionary mystery.
他职业生涯都致力于尝试
He has devoted his career to trying
治愈肌肉萎缩症
to cure muscular dystrophy--
一种痛苦的有时甚至致命的退化病
a distressing and sometimes fatal degenerative disease.
他的工作是非常个人的
His quest is very personal.
我第一次接触肌肉萎缩症时真的是无可避免
STEDMAN: My first exposure to muscular dystrophy was inescapadle;
因为我弟弟和我哥哥
my younger and my older brother
都患上了先天性肌肉萎缩症
both born with muscular dystrophy.
肌肉萎缩症是一种基因病
NARRATOR: Muscular dystrophy is a genetic discase.
患者体内一个基因发生了突变 使得肌肉
Its sufferers have a mutation in one gene that robs their muscles
无法进行自我修复
of the ability to repair themselves.
斯特德曼：平常锻炼时 这些石头 可以损害
STEDMAN: Typical workout here on the rocks might blow through
好几千个肌肉细胞 但它们隔夜便能再生
a few thousand muscle cells,but they'll regenerate overnight
而且 第二天我再进来的时候
and,if anything,be a little stronger the next day I come in
肌肉还能因此变得更强一点
as a result of all of that.
然而 患了肌肉萎缩症后 损伤过程
Whereas ie muscular dystrophy,the injury process is
大大加速 并且损伤速度超过了
greatly accelerated and the injury process outstrips
其修复速度
the body's ability to repair.
为了找寻治愈良方 斯特德曼正研究数百个
NARRATOR: In search of a cure,Stedman is investigating the hundreds
控制肌肉生长的基因
of genes that control the development of muscles.
因此 当人类基因组计划开始实施时
So when the Human Genome Project took off,
斯特德曼抓住了机会
Stedman seized his chance.
斯特德曼：借助整个人类基因组计划的力量后
STEDMAN: When the horsepower of the entire Human Genome Project
我们很清楚我们该找寻什么
kicked in,we knew exactly what to look for.
斯特德曼要找寻的是任何构成肌肉的基因
NARRATOR: Stedman was hunting for any new muscle-making genes.
因此 照着人类基因组序列
And so,as the human genome was sequenced,
他开始筛选如山堆积的数据
he began sifting through the vast mountains of data.
最终 他找到了
Eventually he found what he was looking for--
一个以前不明的肌肉组成基因
a previously unidentified muscle-making gene.
但这个新基因有些奇怪
But there was something strange about this new gene.
它并不像任何其他的肌肉组成基因
It didn't look like any other muscle-making genes.
上面缺失了两个DNA碱基
Two letters were missing.
正是这种基因会引起疾病
This gene should cause a disease.
斯特德曼：一切都很清楚了
STEDMAN: It become very clear early on
如果早期发生这种基因突变的话
that if you have a mutation of this type,
将会产生很严重的肌肉病
you get some serious muscle problem going on.
这真是个谜
NARRATOR: Here was a puzzle.
为何人类会携带一个明显缺陷的基因呢
Why would humans carry a gene that was clearly damaged?
或许这仅仅是个数据上的失误
Perhaps it was simply a mistake in the data.
斯特德曼决定深入研究
Stedman decided to dig a little deeper
并参与其他的人类基因组计划
and look in another human subject.
斯特德曼：说真心话
STEDMAN: In the department of true confessions,
我们首先在自己身上进行实验
we do ceitain experiments first on ourself,
这都是为了方便起见
largely out of convenience.
擦拭了酒精之后 你就能马上研究DNA了
You can swab your own cheek and get working on some DNA.
令他惊异的是
NARRATOR: To his utter amazement,
他在自己体内也找到了相同的缺陷基因
he found the same damaged gene in himself.
我正研究我自己的DNA,
I'm seeing this in my own DNA,
这似乎表明  等等
and it's suggesting that Wait a minute.
似乎我身上也有某种肌肉病
That means there's a muscle disease here somewhere,
只是我没意识到而已
a muscle disease that I'm unaware of.
我想或许值得检查一下
And I thought it would be worth checking this out
实验室的其他同事
in some other members of the lab.
几次擦拭酒精之后
NARRATOR: A few swabs later and...
斯特德曼：显然 那天结束之后
STEDMAN: Sure enough,at the end of the day,
发现在每个人的DNA的相同位置
every single person had the same glitch
都找到了相同的问题
in their same DNA at the same place.
这可真是个谜
NARRATOR: Here then was a real mystery.
似乎这种肌肉组成基因在人体内
It seemed that this particular muscle-making gene
广泛存在
was common in humans.
他在类人猿中也发现了相同的基因
But when he identified the same gene in apes,
和其他肌肉组成基因一样的基因
it was just like any other muscle-making gene.
为何会有区别呢
Why was there such a difference?
为何这种基因使得一种物种能
What did this gene enable one species to do
做其他物种所不能的
that the other could not?
斯特德曼 开始研究类人猿中这一基因所扮演的角色
Stedman began to research the role of this gene in apes.
他发现这一基因构成了一种特殊肌肉
And he found it made one particular kind of muscle--
咀嚼肌
the muscle for chewing.
实际上 这种肌肉用来合拢下巴
In fact,the muscle used to close the jaw.
对人类来说 这种基因遗传意味着
In humans,that genetic glitch meant that we chew
跟类人猿相比 我们只是用一小部分力量来咀嚼
with just a fraction of the force of an ape.
这本身很有趣
This in itself was interesting,
然而斯特德曼接下来研究的才真有趣
but where Stedman went next was truly intriguing
同时 也极具争议
and highly controversial.
他把我们
He drew a direct connection
下颌肌肉的力量
between the power of our jaw muscle
和人类大脑的进化直接联系起来
and the evolution of the human brain.
斯特德曼是这么想的
Stedman's thinking goes like this.
类人猿和人类的头骨
The skulls of apes and humans
是由几块独立的骨板组成的
are made of several independent bone plates.
这些骨板使得我们的头随着发育逐渐长大
They let our heads get bigger as we grow.
而用于咀嚼的肌肉拉扯着这些骨板
The muscles for chewing pull against these plates.
这力量可是巨大的
And in an ape,these forces can be enormous.
斯特德曼：在大猩猩中 这块肌肉
STEDMAN: In the gorilla,the muscle-
有人类大腿肌肉那么大
the size of a human thigh muscle--
长在这儿 并且得穿过这么大的空间
lives here and has to go through this large space
来使下颌前后移动
to power the jaw moving back and forth.
我们并不是在谈论二头肌 也不是三头肌
We're not talking biceps,tricep,
而是四头肌
we're talking quad here.
这可是块大肌肉
This is an enormous muscle
它得穿过这个洞
that has to come right through this hole here
来启动关闭下颌装置
to power the jaw-closing apparatus.
斯特德曼 认为 在初期 这些所有的肌肉
NARRATOR: Stedman contends that all this muscle power
都迫使类人猿的颅骨板融合在一起
forces an ape's skull plates to fuse together at an early stage,
而这也限制了大脑可以长到多大
and this puts limits on how much the brain can grow.
斯特德曼：在黑猩猩 大猩猩或者猩猩中
STEDMAN: In a chimpanzee,gorilla,orangutan,
在他们大约三到四岁时
those growth plates are pretty much shut down,
这些骨板几乎都停止了生长
closed for business by about three,four years of age.
而人类中 他们却能长到30岁左右
In a human,they remain open for growth to perhaps age 30.
斯特德曼认为 这 就是关键
NARRATOR: This,Stedman believes,is the key.
下颌肌肉的突变 使得人类头骨
A mutation in our jaw muscle allows the human skull
不断发育至成年
to keep expanding into adulthood,
我们的大脑也有了更大的空间
creating a bigger space for our brain.
因此我们人类最重要的器官就能发育成长了
And so our most important organ is able to grow.
某种肌肉改变的突变可能
It's very cool to us to think that some kind
会是人类成为独特物种
of muscle-altering mutation might have actually been
的标志性事件
a signature event in the evolution
这想想就很让人激动
of what makes us distinct as a species.
这很可能是我们之所以成为我们
It might have been an absolute prerequisite
的绝对先决条件
for us landing where we are today.
然而 有了一个可以容纳大脑的空间是一回事
NARRATOR: But having the space for a big brain is one thing.
而要想长出大脑需要什么又是另一回事了
What is needed to actually grow one?
这正是 克里斯 沃尔什 试图回答的问题
That is the question that Chris Walsh is trying to answer.
他是未科学家 可从没想过
he's another scientist who never expected
他将从事连达尔文都不明白的事情
to be taking on what even Darwin didn't know.
沃尔什：我从未想过我将研究进化
WALSH: I never thought that I'd be studying evolution.
我是一名神经学家
I'm a neurologist
对研究大脑和和患有神经问题的儿童很感兴趣
interested in the brain and kids with neurological broblems.
你好 伙计 还好吗
How you doing,buddy? Are you doing all right,huh?
你还好吗
You doing okay?
当发现研究这些残疾儿童
No one was more surprised than us
会涉及到那些迷人的进化史问题时
to find that the study of kids with disabilities would lead us
我想没人比我们吃惊
into these fascinating evolutionary questions.
他白天呼吸还好么
Is his breathing generally okay during the day?
当他收到惊吓的时候 会比较快就像...
Sometimes when he gets started,it will go up fast,like...
喘气声
(panting)
但当他冷静下来的时候 就不会了
...but then he calms himself right back down...
沃尔什 是 一种罕见疾病---头小畸形 方面的专家
NARRATOR: Walsh is a specialist in a rare disorder called microcephaly.
头小畸形患儿生下来时头
Children with microcephaly are born with brains
就只有正常的一半大
that can be half the normal size.
沃尔什：这种疾病对患儿
WALSH: This disorder can be very devastating
危害极大
for the kids that have it.
他们通常智力迟钝
They typically will have severe mental retardation,
因此无法正常的语言习得
and so will not be able to achieve normal language
和接受教育
and normal schooling.
这种事情制约着整个家庭
And so it's really an event that defines the whole family.
不仅仅是患儿本身
It defines the lives not only of the child,
还有患儿的父母亲
but of the parents of that child.
这些家庭都迫切希望
And these families are desperately eager
至少了解
to try to understand at least
到底是什么引起了这种疾病
what caused the disorder in their kids.
沃尔什 这项工作最初的目的在于
NARRATOR: The purpose of Walsh's work
帮助那些可能携带
was initially to help families that might be carrying
任何导致头小畸形病的
any defective genes causing microcephaly
缺陷基因
to plan their lives.
我们能为这些家庭提供预测测试
We're able to offer those families predictive testing,
所以 如果他们计划再生小孩的话
so that if they're planning on having additional children,
我们就能提前告诉他们
we can tell them ahead of time
婴儿是否会受到影响
whether that child is likely to be affected or not.
首先 沃尔什 得弄清楚哪儿能找到这些
NARRATOR: First Walsh had to decide where to look in the vast genome
可能导致头小畸形病的基因组
to find any possible microcephaly-causing genes.
于是 他专注于研究DNA中的某一特定区域
So he focused on one particular area of DNA.
因为其他研究表明 这一区域有
Other research suggested it contained a gene
一种特定基因
involved in the condition.
在果蝇和小鼠体内
That gene is known to control
这种基因控制着大脑细胞
how and when brain cells divide in animals,
何时分裂 如何分裂
such as fruit flies and mice.
这种基因似乎控制着大脑
What this gene seems to do is help control
的基本决策
the fundamental decision that the brain has to make,
比如得何时停止细胞分裂
which is "When do I stop making cells?
大脑何时算足够大
When is the brain big enough?"
接着 他的团队开始在
NARRATOR: Then his team began searching
具有病史的家庭中寻找这种相同的基因
for that same gene in a family with a history of the disease.
果然 他们有所发现
And sure enough,they found something.
他们找到了一种直接帮助大脑发育的基因
A gene that helps direct brain growth.
关键地是 它是有缺陷的
And crucially,it was defective.
沃尔什决定在其他患者身上验证这一发现
Walsh decided to check this finding in other patients.
沃尔什：一旦我们找到这种基因
WALSH: Once we found this gene,
我们就在头小畸形病患儿中重新排序
we sequenced it in our kids with microcephaly disorder.
我们接二连三地发现那些患儿家庭都存在
And we found that one family after another
一种基因突变
had a disabling change in the gene
使得其原本功能完全丧失
that completely removed its function.
他总共发现了21种会导致
NARRATOR: In total he has found some 21 different mutations
头小畸形病的不同基因突变
responsible for microcephaly.
有些情况是 DNA的某一碱基
Sometimes one of the DNA's chemical letters
换成了另一个
is replaced with another letter.
有些是几个碱基完全缺失
Sometimes letters are missing entirely.
不管是何种缺陷 都使得大脑细胞
But whatever the defect is,they all stop the brain cells
在发育早期就停止了分裂
from dividing at a very early stage of development.
由于他的那些患儿 沃尔什 很确信
Walsh was now certain-- thanks to his microcephaly patients--
他发现了对人类大脑成长至关重要的基因
he had found a gene key to the growth of the human brain.
他决定把在健康人类体内发现的这种基因
Now he decided to compare normal versions of the gene
跟黑猩猩
found in healthy humans with the same gene in chimpanzees,
这与人类最接近的物种  体内相同基因进行对比
our closest relatives.
他的发现着实令人震惊
And what he found was astonishing.
人类的这种基因
The gene in humans was radically different
与黑猩猩体内发现的截然不同
from that found in chimps.
其中发生了重大的基因突变
There had been a large series of mutations.
这些突变很可能是我们大脑进化中
It could be that these mutations were a major factor
的主要因素
in the evolution of our huge brains.
而这一发现来自于
And this discovery came about
沃尔什对他的病人的研究中
only because of Walsh's work with his patients.
我认为了不起的是
I think one of the amazing things for us
研究人类疾病
was the extent to which studying human disease
会意外地给我们
can unexpectedly enlighten us
带来诸如人类进化方面你的启迪
about something like human evolution.
而这仅仅是我们了解
NARRATOR: But this is only the beginning of our understanding
人类大脑进化的开端
of the evolution of the human brain.
这一研究领域正吸引着
It's an area of research that is now attracting scientists
各行各业的专家 达尔文一定会对此感到惊叹
with a range of skills that Darwin would have marveled at.
凯蒂 波拉德 是以为生物统计学家
Katie Pollard is a biostatistician.
她的生活基本都花在鼓捣数字上面
Her life is spent crunching numbers.
波拉德：我热爱我的工作 因为我可以
POLLARD: What I love about my work is geeking out
鼓捣我的电脑 编写程序
ou a computer and writing programs
思考思考生物学问题
and thinking about biology.
实际上 我在做的
And that in doing this,I'm actually working on something
不只是科学家们关心的事情，
that not just scientists care about,
而是每一个人
but really every human being can relate to
都可以深刻探究的问题 是什么让我们之所以成为人类
and cares profoundly about,and that's what makes us human.
波拉德 以构建了一个庞大的计算机程序
NARRATOR: Pollard has constructed an ambitious computer propram.
它旨在标记那些
It's designed to highlight DNA
像类人猿和其他动物中类似的
that is similar in apes and other animals,
而又和人类非常不同的DNA
but which is very different in humans.
通过这个 她希望能找到那个使得我们之所以是我们的关键DNA
That way,she hopes to identify the key DNA that mades us,us.
波拉德：在这1500万
POLLARD: Out of these 15 million letters
个能够把我们和黑猩猩区分碱基中
that make humans different from chimps,
我们得设法弄清楚那些事重要的
we need to try to figure out which ones were important.
因此 我们采用技术来寻找
And so we use a technique which is to look for places
我们和黑猩猩不同
where human is different from chimp,
而黑猩猩和其他动物几乎相同的地方
but chimp looks almost identical to the other animals.
她也在寻找和人类大脑相关的DNA
NARRATOR: She too is looking for DNA relating to the human brain.
无论是从复杂性上还是尺寸上来说
POLLARD: The brain is one of the things that's changed the most
大脑 是人类进化过程中
during human evolution,
变化最大的
both in terms of its complexity and its size.
同样地 当我们试图寻找
And so when we look to find the parts
那些使得我们人类之所以为人类的基因组时
or our genome that make us human,
我们也对探寻这些基因
we're particularly interested in finding out whether
是否跟大脑相关很感兴趣
these are things that are involved in the brain.
波拉德把人类和黑猩猩中
NARRATOR: It is a huge feat of number crunching,
的DNA序列都载入进去
as Pollard loaded in DNA sequences
这可是巨大的运算量
from both humans and chimps.
波拉德：基本上你得找到一堆电脑硬盘
POLLARD: You basically take a bunch of computer hard drives
把他们堆叠起来
and you stack them up together.
这样我们就能在一个下午的时间
We were able to take a task that wee Id keoe rue
完成台式机上需要花费35年
for 35 years on a desktop computer
才能完成的工作量
and do it in one afternoon.
那天傍晚，
NARRATOR: And at the end of that afternoon,
他们得到了一整叠的材料
they had a whole array of material
上面绘着人类和黑猩猩之间的种种差异
charting the differences between humans and chimps.
重要的是 很多差异
Importantly,many of those differences
并不是在实际的基因上
were not in the actual genes.
而是在基因开关上
They were in switches.
波拉德：事实证明 大多数差异
POLLARD: It turns out that the vast majority
并非在基因上
are not genes.
而是在那些
Instead they're pieces of our DNA
可以称之为基因开关的DNA序列上
that we can think of as switches--
他们是一些能够开启或关闭附近基因
they're pieces of DNA that turn a nearby gene on or off...
告诉它们何时在我们身体的
that tell it where,in what cells in our body,
哪个组织哪个细胞的何处达到什么程度时运行的DNA片段
in what tissue,at what time or at what level to be operating.
关于这些基因开关 还有些
NARRATOR: And there was something even more intriguing
更有趣的事
about those switches.
大量的 估计有一半以上
A large number of them,more than half,
的DNA片段就在跟大脑有关的基因附近
were nearby a gene that was involved in the brain.
在波拉德的工作中
NARRATOR: In Pollard's work,
一个特殊的DNA片段很显著
one particular piece of DNA stood out.
这种DNA序列在
It was a piece of DNA that is known to be active
胚胎的大脑关键部位发育时
in the development of one of the key parts of the human brain
变得非常活跃
in the embryo...
这就是大脑皮质
the cortex.
大脑皮质就是我们大脑外面那皱皱的一层
The cortex is that wrinkled outer layer of our brain.
它对人类的语言能力 学习音乐和数学
It's vital for those defining human capabilities
至关重要
like language,music and mathematics.
当她把黑猩猩和鸡中的
When she looked at that DNA in chimps
相同DNA序列对比时发现
and compared it to the same DNA in a chicken,
仅有两处碱基不同
it was different in just two letters.
而这与人类却存在着18处不同的碱基
But in humans it was different by 18 letters.
这可是巨大的突变
A massive mutation.
作为科学家，这可绝对是个
This was about as great of a eureka moment as you could have
“尤里卡”时刻 （阿基米德洗澡时若有所思地叫了一声“尤里卡” 从此发现了阿基米德定律）
as a scientist.
这又是个有趣的证据
NARRATOR: So here is another intriguing piece of evidence
它告诉我们DNA是如何塑造人类独有特征的
suggesting how DNA can shape our distinctive human qualities.
现在，我们知道了DNA的许多不同工作方式，
We now know that DNA works in many different ways,
比如通过基因来构造我们的躯体
through genes that make the stuff of our bodies,
通过基因开关来开启或关闭基因
through switches that turn those genes on and off
以及通过DNA序列上的碱基
and through sequences of DNA's chemicals
来启动这些基因开关
that throw those switches.
把这一切都串联起来
Taken together,what this all adds up to
我们最终会发现
is a way that we can at last understand
DNA只要一个小小的改变，就能产生巨大的变化
how small differences in DNA can generate enormous change.
波拉德：基本上 只要改变这些基因开关
POLLARD: Basically,you can make massive changes
就能产生巨大的变化
just changing those switches.
因此 一个小小的变化 几个DNA碱基
So a small change,a couple of DNA letters,could have
也能产生深刻地影响
a profound effect.
因此 达尔文的终极谜题
NARRATOR: And so that final Darwinian puzzle--
人类是如何和类人猿紧密相关却又如此不同
how a human can be so closely related to an ape
正在逐步地获得解答
and yet be so different-- is now slowly being answered.
自达尔文提出他的理论
150 years after Darwin first put forward his grand theory
以解释生物的多样性 经过150年
to explain the great diversity of life,
科学家们秉承着他留下的遗产
the scientists who carry on his legacy have advanced his work
以各种奇妙的方法延续着他的研究
in wondrous ways.
我认为 如果达尔文今日依然活着
I think if Darwin were here today,
他绝对会震惊
he'd be absolutely stunned,
高兴甚至会感动地发现他的理论已经被如此地发扬光大
delighted,even moved to see how much his theory has grown.
塔宾：我们现在所能解释的
TABIN: What we now are able to understand
一方面可能会把他吓跑
on the one hand would just blow him away.
但另一方面我觉得他将会非常满意
But I also think it would give him enormous satisfaction,
因为我们正研究的一切都验证了
because ultimately everything we've been learing validates
他的想法
the things that he said.
贾德森：我觉得达尔文市委非常了不起的科学家
JUDSON: I think that Darwin was a ramarkable scientist
绝对称得上非常出色
and absolutely should be celebrated.
但是 我并不认为他会是进化论的终结
However,I do not think that he was the end of evolution.
相反 我认为他只是给我们开了个头
On the contrary,I think he was the beginning.
他给我们概述了重点
He outlined the major points,but we have discovered more
而我们的发现已经远远超过了他的所想
than I think he would have imagined possible.
当我们庆祝查尔斯 达尔文200岁生日
NARRATOR: As we celebrate the 200th birthday of Charles Darwin
以及他的伟大理论诞辰150周年的时候
and the 150th anniversary of his great work,
关于大自然无穷无尽的演化
there is still much more to understand
依然还有许许多多地方需要我们探究
about how the endless forms of nature have arisen.
同时 为了应付这一挑战
And in rising to that challenge,
我们将继续推进医药发展
it is likely that we will continue to advance medicine
以便更好地了解
and come to a better understanding
我们人类本身
of ourselves as well.
NOVA 的全新“进化”网已经上线了
NOVA has a brand-new Evolution Web site
视频 采访 幻灯片
with dozens of videos,interviews,slide shows
以及进化科学上的最新发现等 应有尽有
and the latest in evolutionary science.
请添加书签 让我们获知你们所想
Bookmark it today and let us know what you think.
一切尽在 pbs.org
Find it at pbs.org.
NOVA主要由以下企业赞助
Major funding for NOVA is provided by the following:
埃克森美孚
ExxonMobil,
承担世界上最艰难的能源挑战
taking on the world's toughest energy challenges.
同时感谢 David H. Koch
And by David H.Koch.
以及...
And...
公共广播公司
And by the Corporation for Public Broadcasting
以及以下给PBS的特别赞助
and by centributions to your PBS station from:
普洛麦格集团
Additional funding by Promega Corporation,
天天新发现
discovering every day.
普洛麦格 生命科学
Promege,the science of life.
同时感谢威斯康辛校友研究基金会
And by the Wisconsin Alumni Research Foundation,
给予威斯康辛大学的鼎力支持
in support of the University of Wisconsin.